I heard a rumor,
我听到谣言，
I heard you used to date Larry Ellison's girlfriend.
我听说你曾经和 Larry Ellison 的女朋友约会。
What happened, he stole it from you.
发生了什么，他从你那里偷走的。
We'll come back to that later,
我们稍后再来讨论这一点，
Larry Ellison, the founder Oracle,
Larry Ellison ， Oracle 的创始人，
he is the fifth richest person in the world,
他是世界第五大富豪，
he owns a Hawaiian island,
他拥有一座夏威夷小岛，
all pay for by databases,
所有费用都由数据库支付，
that's why this class exists, all right.
这就是这个班级存在的原因。
Administrative stuff,
行政方面的事，
so the homework #1,
家庭作业 #1 ，
we do this coming Sunday, the 10th,
我们在星期天， 10 号做，
project #0 is also due the 10th,
项目 #0 也是在 10 号截止，
who here has not started project #0?
在这里谁还没有开始项目 #0 ？
One, why not, two.
一个，为什么不（开始），两个。
Do you know C++?
你知道 C++ 吗？
That a no, do you know C++?
那就是不，你知道 C++ 吗？
Now, okay, you should really start,
好的，你真的应该开始了，
because if if you know zero C++,
因为如果你的 C++ 为零，
it will be a struggle,
这将是一个[斗争]，
and again we're not trying to do this to torture you,
我们这么做不是为了折磨你，
it's really meant to be like,
这真的意味着，
this is what the rest of the course is going to be,
这就是课程的其他部分，
like in terms of the projects,
就项目而言，
if you don't know how to write C++
如果你不知道如何编写 C++ ，
and don't how to debug it,
也不知道如何调试它，
you're going to have problems,
你就会有问题，
printf or standard cout is not a debug method,
printf 或标准 cout 不是调试方法，
you want to use a debugger
你希望使用调试器，
and then project #1 will be released,
然后项目 #1 将发布，
we supposed to go out today,
我们今天应该放出，
probably will come out Friday
可能会在星期五出来，
and that'll be on the buffer pool,
这将在缓冲池上，
which will start teaching in in a week and half.
一周半之后开始教学。
Any questions about homework #1 or project #0?
关于家庭作业 #1 或项目 #0 有什么问题吗？
Okay, all right, jump to the material.
好的，跳到材料。
So last class we spent time talking about SQL
上一节课，我们讨论了 SQL ，
and all the modern things,
以及所有现代的东西，
you can do with the CTE, LATERAL JOINs, nested queries, window functions and so forth.
你可以做 CTE ，横向连接，嵌套查询，窗口函数等。
Prior to that we talked about the relational model and relational algebra,
在此之前，我们讨论了关系模型和关系代数，
And so at this point,
在这一点上，
that's the logical view of what the database system is going to look like,
这就是我们将要看到的数据库系统的逻辑视图，
that we're going to, we're sort of mentally construct throughout the rest of the semester,
在这学期剩下的时间里，我们在某种程度上是在构思，
so we're not going to go back to these, discuss these things,
所以我们不会回到这些，讨论这些事情，
but we'll see how we need to know what SQL looks like relational model is,
但我们将看到，我们需要知道 SQL 是什么样子的关系模型，
in order to build the various parts of the system,
为了构建系统的各个部分，
we'll be discussing going forward.
我们将继续讨论。
So as I said at the end end of last class,
就像我在上节课结束时说的，
this point forward in the semester going forward up to around Thanksgiving is going, is going to be
在感恩节之前，这学期的重点将是，
how to build a, sort of a classic or canonical database, relational database management system.
如何构建一种经典的或规范的关系数据库管理系统。
So the, the outline for going forward,
所以，前进的概述，
we, we've already discussed what relational databases are,
我们已经讨论了什么是关系数据库，
but the, the first four topics here is,
但这里的前四个主题是，
Storage, Execution, Concurrency Control, Recovery,
存储、执行、并发控制、恢复，
these are the the aspects you would need to have
这些都是你需要的方面，
to build a, a full featured, safe, reliable database management system.
为了构建一个功能齐全、安全、可靠的数据库管理系统。
And we'll assume it's going running on a single node,
我们假设它会在一个节点上运行，
because it makes our life easier,
因为它让我们的生活变得更容易，
don't go distribute until you have to.
不在必须的情况下不要去分布式。
And then once we understand what a single node database system looks like,
然后一旦我们了解了单节点数据库系统是什么样子，
we'll, we'll then discuss how to expand this and do distributed databases.
然后我们将讨论如何扩展它，做分布式数据库。
And at the end of the semester,
在学期结束时，
we'll talk a little bit also to about,
我们还将讨论，
how, what other additional features and optimizations we can apply,
什么其他功能和优化可以应用，
which then will be a segue into the advanced class,
这将是高级课程的一部分，
if you want to take that in the Spring.
如果你想在春季学习的话。
So the way to think about a database management system
所以，思考数据库管理系统的方式
and the way the course is laid out is a bunch of layers,
和（思考）课程布局的方式是有一些层，
and the different layers are going to provide different functionality to capabilities for the database system,
不同的层将为数据库系统的功能提供不同的功能，
and they're going to expose an API to whatever the layer is is above it.
它们将把 API 暴露给它上面的层。
And it the, the topics we discuss,
我们要讨论的主题，
again basically how to construct those layers,
是如何构建这些层，
put it all together
将它们放在一起，
and have a full featured database management system.
并拥有一个功能齐全的数据库管理系统。
So the way to think about it is that,
所以，考虑这个的方法是，
the most simplistic viewpoint would be,
最简单的观点是，
the application comes along
应用程序出现，
and you going to issue a SQL query
你将发出一个 SQL 查询，
and that's going to first show up and get parsed,
这个查询将首先显示并被解析，
the string of text of the SQL query gets parsed,
SQL 查询的文本字符串被解析，
run through the query optimizer below that,
然后运行下面的查询优化器，
then we'll start executing whatever the Query Plan is,
然后，我们将开始执行查询计划，
there'll be Access Methods,
将有一些访问方法，
that to actually talk to the the tables or indexes or whatever we're trying to access,
可以与表或索引或我们试图访问的任何内容进行交互，
that'll be a Buffer Pool Manager
这将是一个缓冲池管理器，
to manage the memory for our database system,
用于管理我们数据库系统的内存，
and then at the lowest level will be a Disk Manager,
然后在最低级别将是一个磁盘管理器，
that'll be responsible for reading writing data to disk.
负责将数据读写到磁盘。
And so today's class,
所以今天的课程，
we're going to start,
我们将，
getting the semester at the bottom and then work our way up,
这一学期从下面开始，然后努力向上，
when we get to something like a Concurrency Control, Recovery,
当我们达到比如并发控制、恢复的时候，
that's going to permeate throughout the entire system,
这将[渗透]到整个系统，
so we have to come back and revisit all these things,
所以，我们必须回来，重新审视所有这些事情，
when we're running transactions, we need to know what's on disk,
当我们运行事务时，我们需要知道磁盘上有什么，
we need to know what we're accessing, how we're accessing it,
我们需要知道我们正在访问什么，我们如何访问它，
what, what queries we're executing, right.
我们正在执行什么查询，
So the Storage, Execution will get us through the entire stack
所以，存储、执行将帮助我们完成整个[堆栈]，
and then we'll come back and touch it all over again,
然后我们将返回并再次触摸它，
that sounds weird,
这听起来很奇怪，
but we'll look at it all over again.
但我们将重新审视它。
The same thing for Distributed Databases,
对于分布式数据库，也有相同的事情，
we have to know about all these things in a reliable, safe, distributed database.
我们需要知道所有这些信息在一个可靠、安全、分布式的数据库中。
Okay?
好的？
All right, so for the system, we're going to discuss,
好的，对于我们要讨论的系统，
the methods we going to discuss this semester.
我们在本学期要讨论的方法。
We're going to assume that the architecture of what we're trying to build,
我们假设我们尝试构建的体系结构，
again, think conceptually we're construct in our minds,
在概念上出现在我们的脑海中，
a database management system
一个数据库管理系统，
and Bustub is one implementation of this.
Bustub 是这个的一种实现。
We're going to say we're building what is called
我们将会说，我们正在构建的是，
a disk-based database system or a disk-oriented architecture.
基于磁盘的数据库系统或面向磁盘的体系结构。
And this is where the database management system itself is going to assume that,
这就是数据库管理系统本身将假设，
the primary storage location of the database is going to be on some non-volatile disk,
数据库的主存储位置将位于某个非易失性磁盘上，
could be an SSD, a spinning disk hard drive,
可以是固态硬盘，可能是旋转磁盘硬盘，
if you're running the cloud, could be S3,
如果你运行在云上，则可能是 S3 ，
assuming that it's going to be disk-based.
假设它是基于磁盘的。
And all the things we're going to build in our database system
我们要在我们的数据库系统中构建的所有东西
are really designed to now,
都已经设计好，
coordinate or orchestrate the movement of data back and forth from disk into memory.
协调数据在磁盘和内存之间的来回移动。
This should not be news for anyone,
这对任何人来说都不应该是新闻，
this is the classic Von Neumann architecture,
这是经典的[]架构，
where the data is at rest on disk,
其中数据位于磁盘上，
we can't operate it,
我们不能操作它，
unless we bring it into memory,
除非我们把它放入内存，
and then the CPU can do whatever it needs to it.
然后 CPU 可以对它做任何它需要的事情。
So this is, this is the overall theme of what we're trying to build,
所以这是我们试图建立的总体主题，
and this is obviously going to be super hard,
显然这将是非常困难的，
and again, if you're an application developer,
同样，如果你是一名应用程序开发人员，
you don't want to be doing this yourself in your application code,
你不会希望自己在应用程序代码中执行此操作，
you want a database system,
你想要一个数据库系统，
that knows how to do this reliably and safely and correctly and efficiently,
知道如何可靠、安全、正确、高效地做到这个，
to do it for you.
为你做到这个。
So the way to think about what storage looks like
所以，考虑存储是什么样子的，
from our perspective as from a database system is,
从我们作为数据库系统的角度是，
in terms of this hierarchy,
从这个层次结构的角度，
and you might have seen this in other classes or other other textbooks,
你可能在其他课程或其他教科书中看到过这个，
and the way to think about this is that,
思考这一点的方法是，
going from the bottom to the top,
从下到上，
the, the storage devices are going to get faster, but smaller and more expensive,
存储设备将变得更快，但更小，更贵，
so at the bottom layer here,
所以，在最底层，
you have something like network storage,
你可以使用类似网络存储的东西，
this would be EBS or S3,
这应该是 EBS 或 S3 ，
I think in in the textbook,
我想在教科书中，
there's a layer below this,
这下面有一层，
they have tape drives,
他们有磁带机，
but nobody runs database systems off those anymore.
但现在没有人再使用它来运行数据库系统。
But like as you go up,
随着你向上，
after network storage
在网络存储之后，
and you have like a locally attached spinning disk hard drive,
你有一个本地连接的旋转磁盘硬盘，
and then you have maybe like an SSD
然后你可能有 SSD ，
and then after that you have DRAM,
然后你有 DRAM ，
then CPU caches
然后 CPU 缓存，
and now CPU registers, right.
然后 CPU 寄存器，
CPU registers are super fast,
CPU 寄存器速度超级快，
it's the fastest kind of [] you can have,
这是你能拥有的最快的[]，
but like we're talking,
但就像我们谈论的那样，
you have maybe, I don't know,
你可能有，我不知道，
32 registers on your CPU
CPU 上有 32 个寄存器，
and each one's going to be about 64 bits, right,
每个寄存器是 64 位，
you can't store a lot of space in there,
你不能在那里储存很多空间，
store a lot of things in there,
在那里储存很多东西，
but they're going to be super fast.
但它们的速度会非常快。
So from our perspective in this semester,
所以，从我们这学期的角度来看，
the only thing we really care about is this division line here,
我们真正关心的是这里的分界线，
and that's between volatile and non-volatile storage,
这介于易失性存储和非易失性存储之间，
obviously, what does volatile mean,
显然，易失性是什么意思，
we have volatile storage.
我们有易失性存储器。
What's that?
那是什么？
Yeah, it says data gone, when you when you when you power is gone,
是的，它说当你断电时，数据就会消失，
you pull the plug on your DRAM or your CPU registers,
你拔下你的 DRAM 或 CPU 寄存器的插头，
like everything gets wiped out,
所有的东西都被抹去了，
when you boot the systemt back up,
当你重新启动系统时，
nothing's still there.
什么都没有了。
Non-volatile basically means that you write data to the device,
非易失性意味着你将数据写入设备，
and assuming that you make the calls to tell them,
假设你进行调用告诉他们，
get flushed, or you get back an acknowledgement,
被刷新或得到确认，
we'll cover that later,
我们将在稍后讨论这一点，
then we assume that data is going to be persistent,
然后我们假设数据将是持久的，
and that no matter if we restart the system, pull the power,
不管我们重新启动系统，拔下电源，
take the machine out, put it into another location, whatever,
取出机器，把它放到另一个位置，不管是什么，
when we come back, that our data will be there.
当我们回来的时候，我们的数据都会在那里。
Of course, database systems, we don't trust the hardware,
当然，数据库系统，我们不信任硬件，
we don't trust the OS too,
我们也不信任操作系统，
we'll get that in a second,
我们很快就会讲到，
we don't trust any of,
我们对任何一个都不信任，
so we're going to do a bunch of extra stuff
所以我们要做一堆额外的工作，
to make sure that if we write stuff,
以确保如果我们写东西，
maybe we write to multiple locations,
也许我们会写到多个位置，
where we write a backup for it, right,
我们为它写备份，
a bunch of things we'll do
我们将做一系列的事情，
to make sure that we we truly get non-volatile storage.
来确保我们得到真正的非易失性存储。
But from the design of the, the architecture itself,
但是从架构本身的设计来看，
we'll assume that you know, it's volatile versus it non-volatile.
我们会假设它是易失性的，而不是非易失性的。
Another key difference we're going to see between volatile and non-volatile is
我们将看到易失性和非易失性之间的另一个关键区别是，
how we can access the data,
我们如何访问数据，
so non-volatile storage will be considered to be byte addressable,
非易失性存储被认为是字节可寻址的，
what does that mean?
那是什么意思？
Each, he says, you can query each individual byte, correct.
他说，你可以询问每个单独的字节，正确。
So let's say I have one megabyte file,
假设我有一兆字节的文件，
I want to get 64 bits at some random offset,
我想在某个随机偏移量上获得 64 位，
I can do that in memory,
我可以在内存中做到这个，
there's cache lines, is not exactly true,
有高速缓存行，并不完全正确，
but for now we can ignore that,
但现在我们可以忽略这个，
in a non-volatile storage,
在非易失性存储中，
like, think of it an SSD,
比如，想象一下 SSD ，
you can't go get exactly 64 bits in a one megabyte file,
你不能在一个 1 兆字节的文件中获得准确的 64 位，
you got to go get the block that that 64 bits is in,
你必须去获取 64 位所在的块，
bring that into memory
把它放到内存中，
and then do whatever you need on it,
然后在它上做任何你需要的事情，
so you can only address blocks, not individual bytes.
所以，你只能寻址块，而不能寻址单个字节。
And so the reason why this matters is that,
这个很重要的原因是，
there'll be certain algorithms we choose in the design of our system,
在我们的系统设计中，我们会选择某些算法，
where we know we're fetching blocks instead of single bytes or byte offsets,
我们知道我们读取的是块，而不是单个字节或字节偏移量，
and therefore we'll choose maybe an algorithm that is better for block adjustable data,
所以我们将选择一种更适合于块可调整数据的算法，
related to this, we're also going to choose potentially algorithms,
与此相关，我们还将选择潜在的算法，
that maximize the amount of sequential access of our data.
以最大化对数据的顺序访问量。
So what do I mean by this?
那么我这么说是什么意思？
So he said accessing adjacent blocks are are cheaper,
他说，访问相邻块的成本更低，
so we want to do that as much as possible,
所以，我们希望尽可能地做到这个，
so again, say I want to get, I want to get 10 megabytes
所以，比如，我想要获取 10 兆字节，
and I have in [program] to 1 megabyte blocks,
我有[程序]到 1 兆字节，
if those 1 megabyte blocks are scattered in different locations,
如果这些 1 兆字节的数据块分散在不同的位置，
then it's called random access,
那么它被称为随机访问，
go jump to those different locations to get that data,
去那些不同的地方去获取数据，
or alternatively, if it's all aligned together, contiguous,
或者，如果它们都连续排列在一起，
then in theory, I can do one fetch command,
那么理论上，我可以执行一个 FETCH 命令，
I'm not saying what the device is,
我不是说这个设备是什么，
but it's one fetch command to go get those 10 1 megabyte blocks
但只需一个 fetch 命令就可以获取 10 个 1 兆字节块，
and that's gonna be way more efficient, right.
这样效率会高得多。
If you just think of like on a website or download something about the Internet,
如果你只是，想像在一个网站上或下载一些关于互联网的东西，
if I can go open up a single connection and get all the data,
如果我可以打开一个单一的连接，并获得我需要的所有数据，
I need rather than opening up different connections,
而不是打开不同的连接，
the the one fetch, it's going to be faster.
一次 fetch ，这将是更快的。
At the hardware level,
在硬件层面，
think of like a spinning disk hard drive
可以把它想像成一个旋转磁盘硬盘，
and laptops don't come with these anymore,
笔记本电脑不再附带这些，
they still exist in the enterprise world,
它们仍然存在于企业界，
but there's, there's a physical arm that's spinning around on a platter,
有一只有形的手臂在盘上旋转，
like a vinyl record, right,
就像一张黑胶唱片，
like that old people have,
就像老人所有的，
and so if you had to plot move the arm to get data,
所以，如果你必须通过移动手臂来获得数据，
moving that arm is it's a physical thing,
移动手臂是一件物理上的事情，
it's expensive,
它很昂贵，
it's you're actually moving something through through [helium],
你实际上是在通过[氦]移动一些东西，
but you're moving something, moving the arm on the platter.
但你移动一些东西，在盘上移动手臂。
If I have to, if I can just move the arm once
如果我只需移动手臂一次，
and then read a bunch of data without moving it again,
然后不再移动一次就可以读取一大堆数据，
that's sequential access,
这就是顺序访问，
that's to be faster,
这会更快，
if I had to pick the arm up and move it over and over again,
如果我必须拿起手臂，一遍又一遍地移动它，
then that's going much slower.
那么速度会慢得多。
And again, we'll see this,
我们将看到这一点，
when this come up in the execution algorithms,
当执行算法出现时，
that certain algorithms will choose that will maximize sequential access.
某些算法将被选择以最大化顺序访问。
And we'll choose those over something that's more random access,
我们会选择那些，而不是更随机访问的东西，
and this is different than maybe how you think about algorithms in intro classes,
这可能不同于你在入门课程中对算法的看法，
because in that world,
因为在那个世界里，
they assume everything's always going to be the memory, access is always the same,
他们假设一切都是内存，访问总是相同的，
in our world, we're dealing with real hardware,
在我们的世界里，我们处理的是真正的硬件，
so we can't make that assumption.
所以我们不能做出这样的假设。
All right, so, let me talk about,
好的，所以，让我讨论，
so the way we'll think about this is that,
所以我们思考这个问题的方式是，
I'll use the term memory in this class
我会在这节课上使用术语内存，
and I'll just mean here. I'll just mean, mean DRAM,
我的意思只是 DRAM ，
and when I say disk,
当我说磁盘的时候，
I'm going to mean anything below that, right,
我的意思是这下面的所有，
so an SSD, spinning disk hard drive or a network cloud storage.
SSD ，旋转磁盘硬盘或网络云存储。
The, the, the ones up here, the CPU registers,
上面的 CPU 寄存器，
we won't discuss these in this class,
我们不会在这门课上讨论这些，
in the advanced class,
在高级课程中，
we'll talk about different algorithms of the methods to
我们将讨论不同算法的方法，
try to maximize the amount of processing being do of data in CPU registers or L3 L2 caches,
试图最大限度地处理 CPU 寄存器或 L3 L2 缓存中的数据，
and in that world, you can make a huge difference.
在那个世界里，你可以做出巨大的改变。
It's also worth noting,
还值得注意的是，
there are some emerging hardware devices or hardware,
现在有一些新兴的硬件设备或硬件，
that's available today that spans different layers,
可以跨不同的层使用，
so you can get sort of fast network storage or disaggregated storage or disaggregated memory,
你可以获得某种快速网络存储或分散存储或分散内存，
where this looks like,
就像这样，
it could potentially could be by addressable,
它可能是可寻址的，
but you're going over a physical network,
但你是通过物理网络进行的，
so it's a little bit slower,
所以速度会稍微慢一些，
so it sort of straddles in between here.
所以它横跨在这之间。
And then there was something called persistent memory,
然后有一种叫做持久内存的东西，
that people have been dreaming about for a long time,
人们梦想了很长时间，
that would have the benefits, have the by addressability of DRAM,
这将具有 DRAM 的可寻址能力，
but also the persistence of of an SSD
以及 SSD 的持久性，
and it would actually sit in the [dim slot],
并且它实际上将位于[暗槽]中，
so you could write to it as if it was memory,
所以你可以把它当做内存来写，
but if you pull the plug, everything gets retained.
但如果你拔下插头，一切都会保留下来。
And this is something when I, when I first started CMU, 10 years ago,
这是 10 年前，我刚在 CMU 的时候，
we were spending a lot of time researching this,
我们花了很多时间研究的东西，
this is something that was very interesting about,
这是一件非常有趣的事情，
because if we had this persistent memory,
因为如果我们有这种持久内存，
basically all the stuff that I'm going to talk about in two weeks,
基本上我两周时间要谈论的所有东西，
actually, project one in this class basically goes away, right,
实际上，这门课的项目 #1 就基本结束了，
because I don't need to worry about moving things in and out of disk,
因为我不需要担心将东西移入和移出磁盘，
everything in memory is persistent.
内存中的任何东西是持久的。
They might know if anybody actually to make this,
他们可能知道有没有人实现这个，
this persistent non-volatile memory.
这个持久的非易失性内存。
Yes, boom, there you go.
是的，砰，这就对了。
Yes, so he said you could try this with an SSD,
是的，他说，你可以用 SSD 来尝试，
asked people to do that,
要求人们这样做，
but that's not true persistent memory.
但那不是真正的持久内存。
Or then you said Intel OPTANE,
或者你说的 Intel OPTANE ，
Intel OPTANE actually was an SSD,
Intel OPTANE 实际上是一种 SSD ，
it was actually phase change memory,
这实际上是相变内存，
it actually was a physical device,
它实际上是一个物理设备，
that could do was persistent memory, right,
可以做的是持久内存，
HP had [memory registers],
HP 有内存寄存器，
there was IBM rumored has something,
有传闻 IBM 有一些东西，
Intel is the only one that actually made this.
Intel 是唯一一家真正做到这个的公司。
Who here has heard of Intel OPTANE?
在座的谁听说过 Intel OPTANE？
Well, he obviously yes, very, very few.
嗯，他显然是，非常非常少。
It's, it's already dead,
它已经死了，
so Intel killed it last year,
Intel 去年杀死了它，
basically, Intel hired a new CEO
Intel 聘请了一位新的 CEO ，
and they cut a bunch of divisions
他们削减了一大批部门，
and unfortunately, they cut this,
不幸的是，他们削减了这个，
and this sucks,
这很糟糕，
because like, to me,
因为对我来说，
this is like, this would have been a game changer,
这就像是，这本来可以改变游戏规则，
but Intel couldn't make any money off of it,
但 Intel 无法从中获利，
and what sucks also too is like,
同样糟糕的是，
now no one's going to try this for another decade,
现在没有人会在下一个十年里尝试这一技术，
because if Intel couldn't make money off of it,
因为如果 Intel 不能从中获利，
who will, right.
谁又能呢。
But there was a various projects at different database companies,
但是不同的数据库公司有不同的项目，
they were trying to build database systems just around persistent memory,
他们试图围绕持久内存构建数据库系统，
because again, a bunch of the stuff we had to do
因为同样，我们必须做的一大堆事情，
with moving data back and forth between disk and memory goes away with this.
在磁盘和内存之间来回移动数据会随之消失。
So that's a shame.
所以这是一种遗憾。
Okay, so the reason why we have to be cognizant
好的，我们必须了解，
of what the storage are going to look like is,
存储是什么样子的原因是，
because the performance characteristics,
因为性能特征，
as I said, between these different devices are going to be dramatically different,
正如我所说的，这些不同设备之间截然不同，
and we're going to try to maximize the amount of work we can do
我们将尝试最大限度地提高数据的工作量，
for data when it's in memory,
当数据存储在内存中时，
when we bring something off a disk into memory,
当我们将数据从磁盘移入内存时，
we want to do as much work as we can on that, on that data,
我们希望尽可能多地处理这些数据，
before we throw it away and bring something else into memory, right.
在丢弃数据并将其他数据放入内存之前，
In an ideal world, our database would fit entirely in memory,
在理想情况下，我们的数据库应该完全存储在内存中，
even then you have to write out the disk,
即使这样，你也必须写出磁盘，
but in some cases that's not always possible.
但在某些情况下，这并不总是可能的。
So the way to this,
实现这个的方法是，
at the CPU level, right, a cache miss is going to basically is going one nanosecond,
在 CPU 级别，缓存未命中基本上是一纳秒，
getting out of DRAM is hundred hundred nanoseconds
走出 DRAM 是数百纳秒，
and ssd is about 16 microconds or 16,000 nanoseconds,
而 SSD 大约是 16 微秒或 16000 纳秒，
that's actually pretty good,
这真的很不错，
spinning disk hard drive two, two million nanoseconds
旋转磁盘硬盘是两百万纳秒，
and then EBS can fluctuate,
然后 EBS 可能会波动，
sometimes you get 50 milliseconds, sometimes you get 500 milliseconds,
有时是 50 毫秒，有时是 500 毫秒，
depends on how hot the data is
这取决于数据的热度，
and then tape archives, again this is, this is [glacial],
然后是磁带存档，再说一次，这是[冰冷的]，
you don't, you don't want to build any system off this.
你不想在它上面构建任何系统。
So this, this data comes from,
所以这个数据来自，
this particular data here comes out,
这个特殊数据来自，
there's a Berkeley website and a link there,
这里有一个伯克利的网站和一个链接，
he sort of shows you the trends of the hardware performance
他向你展示了硬件性能的趋势
or the the speeds of these devices over time,
或这些设备随着时间的推移的速度，
it's this, this table has been attributed to Jeff Dean from the early 2000s,
这张表被认为是 Jeff Dean 在 2000 年早期的贡献，
actually I think it might predate him before that.
我认为它可能早于他之前。
And so as humans, it's hard for us to reason about nanoseconds, right,
所以作为人类，我们很难推理纳秒，
like one nanosecond, what does that actually mean
比如一纳秒，这是什么意思，
or, or, you know 2 million nanoseconds. Is that a long time?
或者你知道 200 万纳秒，那是很长的时间吗？
And so there's a simple trick you can do to realize
所以有一个简单的技巧可以让你意识到，
how much, how bad this actually is,
这到底有多大，有多糟糕，
or how much slower things actually get,
或者事情实际上会变慢多少，
if you just change one nanosecond to one second, right.
如果你把一纳秒改为一秒，
So this is a trick,
这是一个小把戏，
that this is something that Jim Gray used to do in the 90s,
Jim Gray 在上世纪 90 年代经常做的，
if you just change one nanosecond to one second,
如果你把一纳秒改为一秒，
now you see how massively slower these other devices are,
现在你可以看到其他设备的速度慢了很多，
you see why you want to keep everything in memory as much as possible, right.
你知道为什么要尽可能地将所有内容都保存在内存中了，
And so you think,
所以你可以想，
like if I have to read a page from a book
如果我必须从一本书上读一页，
and say, you know, doing L1 cache miss would be like me walking at this table and looking in the book, right,
然后说， L1 缓存未命中就像走到桌边，查着书，
or if I have to read from an SSD or DRAM,
或者，如果我必须从 SSD 或 DRAM 中读取，
maybe it's walking over to the library and then finding the book,
可能它会走到图书馆，然后找到那本书，
but if I have to read from a tape archive,
但如果我必须从磁带档案中读取，
it's 31 years. That's equivalent to flying to Pluto, the planet,
那就是 31 年，这相当于飞到冥王星，
and then reading one book.
然后读一本书。
So we want to avoid all of this as much as possible.
所以，我们希望尽可能地避免这一切。
Okay?
好的？
So the sequential versus random,
所以顺序访问和随机访问，
we've occurred this, we, we discussed this already,
我们已经讨论过了，
but again this is going to be a reoccurring theme, throughout the entire semester,
但在整个学期中，这将是一个反复出现的主题，
where again the the database system is going to prefer sequential access over random access,
数据库系统倾向于顺序访问，而不是随机访问，
for both reads and writes,
无论是读还是写，
when spinning disk hard drives, again it makes a huge difference,
当是旋转磁盘硬盘时，这会产生巨大的不同，
but even on SSD,
但是即使是在 SSD 上，
because of the way they, they actually work underneath the covers with the []
因为它们在幕后工作使用[]，
and then doing compaction and so forth,
然后进行压缩等，
you're, you're better off doing batch region writes sequentially as much as possible, right.
你尽可能地按顺序进行批处理区域写入，
All right, so the other system design goals we're going to have
好的，所以，我们将拥有的其他系统设计目标，
and how we choose, how we want to build our system is that,
以及我们如何选择，如何构建我们的系统是，
we want to give the illusion,
我们想要给人一种错觉，
that we are operating with the database entirely in memory,
我们完全在内存中操作数据库，
again, for most databases aren't that big,
再说一次，因为大多数数据库都没有那么大，
most databases are less than 10 gigabytes, right,
大多数数据库的容量都不到 10 GB，
but really massive databases like the terabytes, gigabytes and terabytes, petabytes,
但是非常庞大的数据库，比如 TB ，GB 和 TB PB ，
ideally you want to give the appearance that,
理想情况下你想要给人一种，
everything is already in memory,
一切都已经在内存中了，
even though it actually isn't,
尽管它实际上并不是，
and there's tricks we can do to hide the disk [] and so forth.
我们可以做一些小把戏来隐藏磁盘[]等等。
And then, as since reading writing disk is so expensive,
然后，由于读写磁盘是如此昂贵，
we want to do a bunch of other tricks in our design of our system
我们想在我们的系统设计中做一些其他的技巧，
to avoid prolonged stalls or having the system appear unresponsive, right,
来避免长时间停顿或使系统显示为无响应，
because one that'll frustrate the application or frustrate the user,
因为这会使应用程序或用户感到沮丧，
because they think the system's stuck,
因为他们认为系统卡住了，
but you're really fetching things from disk,
但你实际上是在从磁盘获取数据，
but this also is going to cause other problems,
但这也会导致其他问题，
because if we're holding like a lock on something and we stall,
因为如果我们比如对某个东西加锁而停滞，
because we have to get something from disk or write something from disk,
因为我们必须从磁盘读取东西或从磁盘写入东西，
that's gonna slow down everybody else behind us,
这将减慢我们后面的其他操作的速度，
and have a convoy effect.
并产生护航效应。
So there's a bunch of,
所以有一堆，
you know, for this reason we want to avoid this as much as possible,
出于这个原因，我们想要尽可能地避免这种情况，
and again, because random access is slower than its sequential access,
再说一次，因为随机访问比顺序访问慢，
we want to maximize sequential access.
所以我们希望最大化顺序访问。
So what does this all sound like,
那么，这一切听起来像什么，
having the appearance we have more memory than we actually do,
有了我们比实际拥有更多的内存的[现象]，
virtual memory,
虚拟内存，
so we'll get this in a second,
所以我们稍后会讲到这个，
I'll explain why we don't want to do virtual memory from the OS
我将解释为什么我们不想从操作系统获得虚拟内存，
and why, as a database system developer, engineer building the actual system,
以及为什么作为数据库系统开发人员和构建实际系统的工程师，
we always want to do as much as we can ourselves
我们总是想自己做尽可能多的事情，
and not rely on the OS to do anything.
而不是依赖操作系统来做任何事情。
So, high level, this is our diagram,
所以，从高级别上看，这是我们的图，
this is what we're building,
这是我们正在构建的，
so we have some database file or files, plural,
所以我们有一些数据库文件，
it doesn't matter,
无所谓，
we can discuss the differences,
我们可以讨论不同之处，
we have some database file that's on disk
我们有一些数据库文件在磁盘上，
and we're going to break it up into pages,
我们将把它拆分成页，
and I'll describe what a page in a second,
我稍后会描述一个页，
and there'll be some directory that's going to say,
然后会有一些目录显示，
here's what pages I have, here's where to find them,
这是我拥有的页，这是找到它们的位置，
that's all set and so forth.
一切都安排好了，以此类推。
And then there'll be some buffer pool,
然后会有一些缓冲池，
where of memory the database system is allocated,
数据库系统分配的内存，
basically called malloc against the OS, got some memory,
对操作系统调用 malloc ，获得一些内存，
and then we're going to use that as the staging area
然后，我们将把它用作中转区，
where we bring pages in from disk.
从磁盘调入页。
So now if the execution engine,
所以现在，如果执行引擎，
the thing that's going to run our query comes along
即将运行我们的查询的东西出现，
and it wants to get page #2,
它想要获得第二页，
we can ignore how it knows, it wants page #2 for now,
我们现在可以忽略它是如何知道的想要第二页，
but assumes that's what it wants one, page #2.
但假设这就是它想要的那个，第二页。
So the very first thing we got to do is bring in the page directory,
所以我们要做的第一件事是引入页面目录，
because that's going to tell us where, where on disk the pages are,
因为这将告诉我们页面在磁盘哪里，
and then it'll make a call to the OS
然后它会调用操作系统，
or whatever the device it is that's storing the database file,
或存储数据库文件的任何设备，
and it'll bring that page into memory.
它会把那一页放入内存中。
And then now the buffer pool will give back the execution engine, a pointer in memory,
现在，缓冲池将返回给执行引擎一个内存中的指针，
a 64 bit pointer in memory of where this page exists,
内存中的一个 64 位指针，表明页所在的位置，
and now it's up to the execution engine or the access method, the operators
现在，这取决于执行引擎或访问方法，即操作者，
to then interpret what's inside that page,
然后解释页面中的内容，
because all that's opaque to the, to the rest of the system,
因为所有这些对系统的其他部分来说都是不透明的，
they don't,
他们不会，
it's not entirely true,
这并不完全是真的，
but at this point, they don't really need know.
但在这一点上，他们并不真正需要知道。
And then let's say once you do a bunch of updates,
然后假设一旦你做了一系列更新，
it makes, makes changes to whatever's in page #2,
它就会对第二页中的内容进行更改，
I'm not saying whether it's a tuple,
我不是说它是否是一个 tuple ，
I'm not saying whether it's an index,
我不是说它是否是一个索引，
it doesn't matter.
这并不重要。
And then now the database system is responsible for writing this back out to disk
然后，数据库系统负责将其写回磁盘，
to make sure that any changes are persistent.
以确保任何更改都是持久的。
So this is, this is effectively where we're going for the next three or four lectures,
这就是我们接下来三四节课要讲的内容，
this is the architecture we're going to be building,
这就是我们要构建的架构，
so we'll discuss what pages look like
我们将讨论页面是什么样子的，
in the next three lectures, 3, 4 and 5,
在接下来的三节课中， 3 4 5 ，
we'll discuss how to write things out the disk in 6
我们将讨论如写出磁盘在第 6 节课，
and what, how to manage memory in 6,
以及如何管理内存在第 6 节课，
and then we'll discuss how to execute the queries, appear in 12 and 13.
然后我们将讨论如何执行查询，在第 12, 13 节课中。
So our focus really today is,
所以我们今天真正关注的是，
what are these things on disk?
磁盘上的这些东西是什么？
Okay.
好的。
So I said before, what does this sound like?
所以我之前说过，这听起来像什么？
Everyone said virtual memory
每个人都说虚拟记忆，
and you say, okay, well why do, why take the next three lectures talking,
你说，好的，为什么，为什么接下来的三节课，
about you need this lecture? Why take the next two lectures after that,
你需要这节课，为什么还需要接下来的两节课，
talk about how to manage memory back and forth from disk,
讨论如何在磁盘之间来回管理内存，
when the OS can do that for us.
当操作系统可以为我们做这件事时。
Do you know what's the syscall you would use to use virtual memory in this way,
你知道以这种方式使用虚拟内存的系统调用是什么吗，
mmap, beautiful, excellent,
mmap ，漂亮，很棒，
{so,the,answer,is,memory map file,
所以答案是内存映射文件，
so this is in the POSIX Standard,
这是在 POSIX 标准中，
Windows has their own version of it,
Windows 有自己的版本，
but this allows you to take the contents of a file that's on disk
但这允许你获取磁盘上文件的内容，
and you map it into virtual memory in your process,
并将其映射到进程中的虚拟内存中，
in the address of your process,
在你的进程的地址中，
and then now that process can jump to any offset in that address space in memory,
现在，该进程可以跳转到内存中该地址空间中的任何偏移量，
and the OS is responsible for deciding,
操作系统负责决定，
oh, is the thing you need in memory or not,
哦，你需要的东西是否在内存中，
if not, then it goes and fetches the page you need
如果不是，那么它会获取你需要的页面，
and brings it in memory, right.
并将其放入内存中。
So the database system doesn't, is not doing any of the [reason] writes,
所以数据库系统没有做任何写入，
it just mmap opens the file
它只是使用 mmap 打开文件，
and the OS does all the management of the data,
操作系统完成所有数据的管理，
moving the data back and forth forth for us.
为我们将数据来回移动。
So it sort of look like this,
所以它看起来有点像这样，
we have an on disk file,
我们有一个磁盘上的文件，
we have a bunch of pages,
我们有一大堆页面，
we call mmap to open it up
我们调用 mmap 来打开它，
and then we'll have a concept of virtual memory and and physical memory,
然后我们就有了虚拟内存和物理内存的概念，
so virtual memory would be what I see in my process address space,
虚拟内存将是我在进程地址空间中看到的，
again, at some starting location, I'll get the, I'll get the mmap file,
在某个起始位置，我会得到 mmap 文件，
and then these virtual memory has to be backed by physical pages,
然后，这些虚拟内存必须由物理页面支持，
so as I touch a page,
所以，当我[触摸]页面时，
the OS has to go, then put it into some space in physical memory,
操作系统必须将其放入物理内存中的某个空间，
and then update the wiring for the virtual memory table, right.
然后更新虚拟内存表的连接。
So that my process wants to touch page #1,
所以我的进程想要接触第一页，
so we would have a page fault,
这样我们就会出现页面错误，
because the OS would recognize,
因为操作系统会意识到，
I don't have page #1 in physical memory,
我在物理内存中没有第一页，
it'll go out the disk, fetch it for me, put it in,
它会取出磁盘，为我取出，放入，
update virtual memory to now, point to it,
更新虚拟内存，指向它，
and then my process can touch it or do whatever wants with it.
然后我的进程可以[接触]它或对它做任何想做的事情。
Same thing, now if I want page 3,
一样的东西，现在，如果我想要第三页，
it's not in there,
它不在那里，
I get a page fault,
我收到一个页面错误，
the OS blocks my process,
操作系统会阻止我的进程，
when I do, when I access it,
当我这样做，当我访问它时，
it goes fetch to the page I need from disk, updates the wiring
它会从磁盘获取我需要的页面，更新连接，
and and then then my process can start running again,
然后我的进程可以再次开始运行，
my thread can start running again.
我的线程可以重新开始运行。
What happens if I want to touch page 2?
如果我想[接触]第二页，怎么办？
what's that?
那是什么？
Is to get rid of it,
它会丢掉它，
but what happens while I'm getting rid of it?
但是当我丢掉它的时候，会发生什么？
My process stalls, right,
我的进程停止了，
I go to, the OS is going to block me,
操作系统会阻止我，
while it says, okay, well I don't have any more physical memory,
它会说，好的，我没有更多的物理内存，
let me go out and figure out what to page 1 or 3,
让我找出应该页面 1 还是页面 3 ，
which one should I throw away, right,
我应该扔掉哪一个，
but the OS is going to have its own internal statistics,
但操作系统会有自己的内部统计数据，
about how these pages are being accessed,
关于这些页面是如何被访问的，
and it's going to make a decision about what page to evict,
它将决定驱逐哪个页面，
but it doesn't know anything about what we're doing inside the database system,
但它不知道我们在数据库系统中做了什么，
because it just sees reads, writes,
因为它只能看到读、写，
it doesn't like a [course screen],
它没有[课程屏幕]，
doesn't know what queries are,
不知道什么是查询，
doesn't know what's in these data pages,
不知道这些数据页面中有什么，
what's in these files,
这些文件中有什么，
so the OS is going to try to make a decision on how to swap things out.
所以，操作系统将尝试就如何将东西换出做出决定。
And that's just for eviction,
这只是为了驱逐，
there's a whole bunch of other problems that we're going to face,
我们将面临一大堆其他问题，
if we rely on the OS to do this for us.
如果我们依赖操作系统来为我们做这件事。
So in my first example here,
所以，在我的第一个示例中，
I shared one thread or one process with accessing it.
我共享了一个线程或一个进程来访问它。
But again, we're going to try to build a database,
同样，我们将尝试建立一个数据库，
a modern database system that can take advantage of multiple cores or multiple CPUs,
一个可以利用多核或多 CPU 的现代数据库系统，
and so we need to have multiple threads access them,
所以，我们需要让多个线程访问它们，
but now, what if one of them,
但是，如果它们中的一个，
you know, one of them touches something, writes it,
其中一个线程创建了一些东西，写入它，
and then another guy tries to read it,
然后另一个线程试图读取它，
but it gets stalled, because it gets evicted,
但它被停滞了，因为它被驱逐了，
the ordering can get kind of screwy,
顺序可能会变得有点古怪，
and again, the operating system doesn't know anything that's going on,
同样，操作系统不知道正在发生的任何事情，
what's running inside the system at the same time.
也不知道同时在系统内运行的是什么。
So everything is read-only, it's okay,
所以如果一切都是只读的，没有问题，
because we're not dirty any pages,
因为我们没有弄脏任何页面，
the OS can swap things out,
操作系统可以把东西换出来，
it'll be good enough,
这已经足够好了，
and there are some cases,
而且也有一些案例，
there are some database systems that do use mmap just for read-only parts of the system.
有一些数据库系统确实只将 mmap 用于系统的只读部分。
But if you now need to have multiple writers,
但是如果你现在需要多个写入者，
which again, in a real system, we're going to want this,
在真实系统中，我们将需要这个，
then there's a bunch of other problems.
然后还有一堆其他的问题。
So the first one is transaction safety,
所以，第一个问题是事务安全，
this is the one I sort of mentioned,
这就是我提到的问题，
if I have a transaction that updates multiple pages,
如果我有一个更新多个页面的事务，
I need to make sure that these pages are actually written out in the right order
我要确保这些页面是以正确的顺序写出的，
and the OS doesn't know that,
并且操作系统不知道这一点，
because it just solves dirty pages,
因为它只解决脏页，
it doesn't know anything about,
它完全不知道，
does this page need to be written before this other page,
这一页是否需要在另一页之前写入，
you can do some things like,
你可以做一些事情，
you can lock the page using mlock,
比如你可以使用 mlock 锁定页面，
but that only prevents the OS from swapping it out,
但这只会阻止操作系统将其换出，
doesn't prevent it from writing out,
而不会阻止它写出，
so now it may write out a dirty page, that it shouldn't have,
现在它可能会写出一个它不应该写出的脏页，
I crash and come back,
我崩溃了，然后又回来了，
and now I have changes that shouldn't have been written a disk,
现在我有了一些不应该写在磁盘上的更改，
and I had to go figure out how to reverse that
我不得不想办法如何扭转这一局面，
or deal with the bad data, inconsistent data.
或者处理坏数据，不一致的数据。
We've already talked about doing stalls,
我们已经讨论过做停滞的事，
again, if you try to access something that's not in memory,
同样，如果你尝试访问不在内存中的内容，
you get a major page fault,
会出现严重的页面错误，
it blocks your thread,
它阻塞你的线程，
deschedules you,
阻止调度你，
the disk scheduler goes get your page, brings it in,
磁盘调度器去获取你的页面，把它带进来，
and when it's available,
当它可用时，
then you get, your thread gets rescheduled again.
你的线程会再次重新调度。
But now your thread is blocked in doing nothing, right,
但是现在你的线程被阻塞，无法执行任何操作，
and it maybe there are other queries you could possibly run,
你可能还可以运行其他查询，
while you're waiting for that thing to fetch, get fetch from disk.
当你在等待那个东西从磁盘获取时。
So then you say, okay, well, maybe I'll make a dispatcher or a scheduler,
然后你会说，好的，也许我会做一个调度器，
so that there's only one thread that goes and gets things
这样只有一个线程去处理和获取东西，
and there's a page fault,
并且有一个页面错误，
he gets blocked and then I can run another, run another threads.
他被阻塞了，然后我就可以再运行其他线程。
But now you kind of, you're building more infrastructure around the limitations of mmap.
但是现在，你围绕 mmap 的限制建立了更多的基础设施。
Next problem you have is, how do you handle errors, right,
你遇到的下一个问题是，如何处理错误，
if I in mmap,
如果我在 mmap 中，
if I try to access a page,
如果我试图访问一个页面，
that for whatever reason it's corrupted or not available,
不管是什么原因，它被损坏或不可用，
there's some hardware problem,
那么就会出现一些硬件问题，
you don't get an exception as you would,
你不会得到异常，
if you write it in user space code,
像在用户空间编写的代码，
you get a SIGBUS and interrupt.
你会得到一个 SIGBUS 和中断。
Now you need a signal handler all throughout the rest of your system,
现在，你需要一个贯穿整个系统其余部分的信号处理程序，
because you may be doing something that is in a critical section,
因为你可能正在执行一些临界区中的操作，
that you don't want to get interrupted or break,
你不希望被中断或打断，
so therefore you have to have an interrupt handler
所以，你必须有一个中断处理程序，
to make sure you can go back to the thing you were doing before,
以确保你可以返回到之前在做的事情，
to handle this interrupt,
为了处理这个中断，
because this is the only,
因为这是唯一的，
this is how the operating system tells you, things are going bad,
这是操作系统告诉你，事情正在变坏，
you can't get back in error code,
你不能返回错误码，
you get back and interrupt.
你可以返回并中断。
Need to say, that's a lot of engineering to handle this,
需要说的是，这需要大量的工程技术来处理，
you don't want to do this.
你不会想要这样做。
And then there's obviously going to be performance issues,
然后，显然会出现性能问题，
and this is because the database, operating system is going to have its own internal data structures,
这是因为操作系统将有自己的内部数据结构，
about what's in memory and not memory,
关于什么在内存中，不在内存中，
what's getting scheduled or not getting scheduled,
什么正在调度或未调度，
and it has to protect those critical sections inside its own data structures,
它还必须保护自己数据结构中的那些临界部分，
with mutexes or whatever,
使用 mutex 或其他什么，
and now that's going to be a contention point,
现在这将是一个争议点，
where as in a database system,
因为在数据库系统中，
since we know what queries are trying to do,
因为我们知道查询要做什么，
because again, SQL is declarative,
因为 SQL 是声明性的，
we know what the queries want to do,
所以我们知道查询要做什么，
because we have the physical plan,
因为我们有物理计划，
we know what the data are trying to access
我们知道试图访问什么数据，
and therefore we can we're in a better decision to decide how to schedule things.
因此我们可以更好地决定如何调度事情。
Yes.
好的。
His question is,
他的问题是，
is the database systems have the privilege to work with hardware directly,
数据库系统是否有权直接与硬件一起工作，
there are methods called kernel bypass,
有一些称为内核旁路的方法，
where you can,
你可以，
or NVMe is sort of like this,
或者 NVMe 是这样的，
there's ways to make calls to hardware without having to rely on the OS.
有一些方法可以在不依赖操作系统的情况下调用硬件。
The problem with those things are,
这些东西的问题是，
you basically have to implement a bunch of the OS back up inside the database system,
你必须在数据库系统中实现一系列操作系统备份，
so there's something called this is a [tangent],
这就是所谓的 tangent ，
if you don't want to have to use the OS's TCP stack for networking,
如果你不想使用操作系统的 TCP 协议栈进行网络，
there's something called the, the DPDK from Intel,
有一个叫做 DPDK 的东西，来自 Intel ，
the Data Plane Data Kit or Development kit,
数据平面开发套件，
basically, it's a way to hook directly in the hardware
基本上，这是一种直接连接到硬件中的方法，
and you get raw packets out,
你可以获得原始数据包，
but again, it's raw packets,
但同样，它是原始数据包，
if it's a TCP connection,
如果它是一个 TCP 连接，
now you gotta keep track of the TCP headers and right.
那么现在你必须跟踪 TCP 头。
Very few database systems do this,
很少有数据库系统能做到这个，
I only know two,
我只知道两个，
one was, one Yellowbrick,
一个是 Yellowbrick ，
we discuss them throughout the semester,
我们在整个学期中都会讨论这些，
they have a bunch of amazing stuff,
他们有很多令人惊叹的东西，
they basically rewrite their own,
他们基本上重写了自己的，
they basically only use the OS to turn the thing on
他们基本上只使用操作系统来打开，
and they never call malloc again,
然后他们永远不会再调用 malloc ，
they allocate all the memory, everything beginning,
他们分配所有的内存，一切都开始了，
they wrote their own PCIe drivers,
他们编写了自己的 PCIe 驱动程序，
they do a bunch of amazing engineering,
他们做了一堆令人惊叹的工程，
few people do that.
很少有人会这么做。
The other was was ScyllaDB,
另一家是 ScyllaDB ，
but the DPDK was so difficult to handle,
但 DPDK 太难处理了，
that was huge pain, they don't do it.
这是巨大的痛苦，他们不会这么做。
So the answer to the question is,
所以这个问题的答案是，
for some things, you have to go through the OS,
对于某些事情，你必须通过操作系统，
in the 80s, they got really crazy
在 80 年代，他们变得非常疯狂，
and like they, instead of using a file system,
他们不再使用文件系统，
they wrote their own storage layer on top of raw block devices,
而是在原始数据块设备上编写自己的存储层，
like people have tried this every years,
人们每年都会尝试这种方法，
from an engineering perspective,
从工程学的角度来看，
it's oftentimes you do have to rely on the OS,
通常情况下，你确实必须依赖操作系统，
but you want to minimize your contact with it,
但你想尽量减少与它的接触，
because the OS is going to be your enemy.
因为操作系统将成为你的敌人。
Other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
I don't spend too much time on mmap,
我没有在 mmap 上花太多时间，
this is suffice say it's a bad idea, don't do it,
这是个坏的想法，不要这样做，
if I die, you know you can put on my tombstone
如果我死了，你可以把它放在我的墓碑上，
never use mmap for your database.
永远不要在你的数据库上使用 mmap 。
And the reason why I I was want to bring this up is because,
我之所以想提出这一点是因为，
you know we invite a lot of these database companies and startups to come give talks at CMU
我们邀请了很多数据库公司和初创公司来 CMU 演讲，
and surprisingly over the last couple of years,
令人惊讶的是，在过去的几年里，
a lot of them mentioned they're using mmap
他们中的许多人提到他们使用了 mmap ，
and we ask them why
我们问他们为什么，
and they say, oh, because it's quick and easy to use
他们说，哦，因为它又快又容易使用，
and then when we go talk to them a few years later,
然后当我们几年后与他们交谈时，
like oh yeah, that was a huge mistake,
他们说，哦，是的，这是一个巨大的错误，
we should not have done mmap,
我们不应该使用 mmap ，
we should have done what lecture six is going to teach you, right.
我们应该做第 6 节课要教你们的。
So here's a listing of some systems that I know using mmap,
下面是我所知道的一些使用 mmap 的系统的列表，
there's a couple others I'm sure I'm missing,
我肯定还有其他几个我错过了，
there's a bunch of hobby projects.
有一堆业余爱好项目。
So the one at the top, these are full usage,
所以，在上面的那些，这些是完全使用，
these are systems,
在这些系统中，
where they entirely use mmap for all of data back and forth from disk and memory.
它们完全使用 mmap 来处理所有数据在磁盘和内存中的来回。
The most famous one of these is probably Elastic,
其中最著名的大概就是 Elastic ，
MonetDB was a construct of CWI,
MonetDB 是由 CWI 构建的，
the same place that build []DB,
也是构建[]数据库的地方，
the LMDB do probably the exact opposite of me,
LMDB 做的可能与我相反，
where I'm saying never use mmap,
我的意思是永远不要使用 mmap ，
he's like always always use mmap
他喜欢一直使用 mmap ，
and he been banned on a bunch of different databases mailing list,
他在一堆不同的数据库邮件列表上被禁止，
because he would email them
因为他会给他们发电子邮件，
and say like you guys should be using,
说你们应该使用，
you should be using LMDB, should using mmap, right,
你们应该使用 LMDB ，应该使用 mmap ，
he's wrong, he.
他错了，他[]。
But here's the ones the partially using it,
但这是部分使用它的人，
actually, I should put Mongo as full usage,
实际上，我应该把 Mongo 放在完全使用，
they should really be at the top,
他们应该在上面，
but the ones at the bottom here,
但是下面的这些，
they all got rid of it, right,
他们都摆脱了它，
because of all the issues that I mentioned before,
由于我前面提到的所有问题，
you can get, you can get something up and running pretty quickly if you use mmap,
如果你使用 mmap ，你可以很快启动和运行一些东西，
because you don't have to build your own buffer pool manager,
因为你不必构建自己的缓冲池管理器，
but because you're lying on the OS to move data back and forth,
但因为你依赖操作系统上来回移动数据，
it's going to make horrible decisions, right.
它将做出可怕的决定。
I'm not going, I don't want to pick Mongo,
我不想选择 Mongo ，
but Mongo is the best example of this,
但 Mongo 就是最好的例子，
Mongo started off with an mmap based storage engine, storage manager
Mongo 从一个基于 mmap 的存储引擎、存储管理器开始，
and they, they were the hot database in the 2010s,
他们是 2010 年代的热门数据库，
they raised a ton of, you know, investor money
他们筹集了大量的投资者资金，
and they had really good engineers,
而且他们有非常优秀的工程师，
so they and they were based on [time] mmap,
他们是基于 mmap ，
if mmap was the right choice,
如果 mmap 是正确的选择，
then they could have, they could have made that work,
他们就可以使它工作，
but what do they do,
但他们做了什么，
they threw it all away
他们把所有的东西都扔掉了，
and they bought WiredTiger
然后购买了 WiredTiger ，
with a storage manager that doesn't use that mmap, right.
它有一个不使用 mmap 的存储管理器。
So again, just to reiterate,
所以，再次重申，
never use, we don't want to use the OS to manage memory,
永远不要使用，我们不想使用操作系统来管理内存，
because the database system is always going to be a better position to do this,
因为数据库系统总是更适合这样做，
and it's not just for managing memory,
而且它不仅仅用于管理内存，
it's basically for everything,
它基本上适用于所有事情，
we don't need the OS for scheduling,
我们不需要操作系统来调度，
we don't want to use OS for caching writes,
我们不想让操作系统来缓存写入，
we don't the use, use the OS for,
我们不需要使用操作系统来，
and the network stuff you need to in some cases,
以及你在某些情况下需要的网络东西，
but there's tricks for that,
但这是有技巧的，
but the OS is always going to be a problem.
但操作系统总是会是一个问题。
And again for mmap,
再次，对于 mmap ，
again, I'll send this link on Piazza,
我将在 Piazza 上发送这个链接，
We wrote a paper about this,
我们写了一篇关于这个的论文，
so why you don't want to use this,
那么为什么你不想用这个，
and then there's there's a 10 minute Youtube video cartoon,
然后有一段 10 分钟的 Youtube 视频卡通片，
about all the problems.
讲述了所有的问题。
So again, the OS is going to be a problem for us,
所以，操作系统将成为我们的问题，
and we have to design our system to deal with it.
我们必须设计自己的系统来处理它。
All right, so for database storage,
好的，对于数据库存储，
there's two problems you got to deal with.
有两个问题要处理。
How are we going to represent the the database on these files on disk,
我们如何在磁盘的这些文件上表示数据库，
and then once we have those,
然后，一旦我们有了这些，
how do we move data back and forth from disk into memory.
我们如何在磁盘和内存之间来回移动数据，
So today's lecture is going to be on the first problem here,
所以今天的课程将讨论第一个问题，
and then we'll cover the second problem in the upcoming lectures.
然后我们将在接下来的课程中讨论第二个问题。
All,right.
好的。
So there's going to be sort of three layers
所以，这里可以分为三层，
of what data is going to look like on these disk pages.
关于磁盘页面上的数据是什么样子的。
So the first question is,
所以第一个问题是，
what do these files actually look like,
这些文件实际上是什么样子的，
and then within a file, there's be pages,
然后在一个文件中，有页面，
because we to break it up into different chunks,
因为我们需要将它分成不同的块，
and then then we'll discuss what these pages look like,
然后我们将讨论这些页面的样子，
and then within that page, we're going to have tuples,
然后在页面中，我们将拥有 tuple ，
the data itself, the tables,
数据本身，也就是表，
we can ignore indexes for now,
我们现在可以忽略索引，
and you have to decide what actually tuples look like.
并且你必须确定 tuple 是什么样子的。
So start at the top and then go deeper, deeper inside of these files
所以从顶部开始，然后深入到这些文件的内部，
to understand what, what they actually contain.
以了解它们实际包含的内容。
So as I said before,
正如我前面所说的，
the database system is going to maintain a database as one or more files on disk,
数据库系统将数据库作为磁盘上的一个或多个文件进行维护，
SQLite, DuckDB, those are all single file databases,
SQLite, DuckDB ，这些都是单文件数据库，
all the enterprise databases or Postgres, MySQL,
所有企业数据库或 Postgres MySQL ，
every other system, you know, more full featured system
每个其他功能更全的系统，
is going to be running, you know, maintaining multiple files for your tables and databases.
都运行，为你的表和数据库维护多个文件。
And so the, the format that these files are going to be based on is typically going to be
所以，这些文件基于的格式通常是，
proprietary or custom to whatever the database system actually is, right,
数据库系统的专有或定制格式，
that meaning like you can't take the Postgres database files
这意味着你不能使用 Postgres 数据库文件，
and open them up in in MySQL
然后在 MySQL 中打开它们，
or open them up in SQLite.
或者在 SQLite 中打开它们。
Now, DuckDB because they want to be portable and compatible with, with SQLite,
现在 DuckDB ，因为他们想要可移植并与 SQLite 兼容，
they have connectors allow you to read, you know, sqlite files and other things,
他们有连接器，你可以读取 SQLite 文件和其他东西，
but in general, all the major database systems are going to have their own proprietary format.
但总的来说，所有主要的数据库系统都拥有自己的专有格式。
And the OS doesn't know anything about what's inside of these files,
操作系统不知道这些文件中有什么，
doesn't know what's inside of a page,
不知道页面中有什么，
doesn't know where indexes are versus tables are,
也不知道索引和表在哪里，
it just knows nothing just sees a bunch of files.
它什么都不知道，只看到一堆文件。
So next class we'll talk about portable file formats,
下一节课我们将讨论可移植文件格式，
things like Parquet, Avro, ORC, Arrow,
比如 Parquet, Avro, ORC, Arrow ，
these are going to be open source specifications for what a database file could look like,
这些将是数据库文件样子的开放源码规范，
and then there's a bunch of database systems,
然后有一堆数据库系统，
that know how to to read them and access them and write them.
知道如何读取、访问和写入它们。
But we'll about those later.
但我们以后会讨论这些。
And as I said before,
就像我之前说的，
in the 1980s, there was a sort of a lot of the earlier database systems decided,
在 1980 年代，有很多早期的数据库系统决定，
that they they not only were they gonna have customized file formats,
他们不仅会有定制的文件格式，
they were also gonna have customized file systems
他们还会有定制的文件系统，
and they weren't going to use, ext3, didn't, didn't exist,
他们不会使用， ext3 不存在，
you know, btrfs didn't exist back then,
btrfs 当时还不存在，
but they, whatever the equipment was in the 80s,
但他们，无论 80 年代的设备是什么，
they didn't even rely on what the OS said, what the file system was,
他们甚至不依赖于操作系统所说的文件系统是什么，
they wanted to do everything themselves.
他们想要自己做所有的事情。
But that's a lot of engineering work
但这是大量的工程工作，
and, and nobody does that today,
而且今天没有人这样做。
and it usually a marginal benefit.
而且这通常是一种边际收益。
The only system that still do this
唯一仍能做到这一点的系统，
would be like what I'll call enterprise systems,
应该是我称之为企业系统的系统，
so this will be an Oracle, the DB2s, the Teradatas,
这个有 Oracle DB2 Teradata ，
these are million Dollar database systems
这些是数百万美元的数据库系统，
that are trying to get as much, much performance as you can,
它们试图获得尽可能多的性能，
these systems will support this,
这些系统还支持这个，
in addition to running off the generic OS file systems.
除了运行通用操作系统文件系统，
So then the, the part of the database system,
然后，数据库系统中的部分，
that's going to be responsible for maintaining and coordinating these different files,
负责维护和协调这些不同文件（的部分），
we'll call generically as the storage manager,
我们通常称为存储管理器，
sometimes it's called the storage engine,
有时它被称为存储引擎，
it's the same idea.
这是同样的想法。
And it's going to be part of the system,
它将成为系统的一部分，
that communicates with the either the hardware
与硬件通信，
or communicates with the hardware or whatever the storage device is,
或与硬件或任何存储设备通信，
either through the OS or using direct direct access
通过操作系统或使用直接访问，
to retrieve data and bring it into the database, database system's memory.
来检索数据，并将其带入数据库系统的内存。
And so we'll discuss this next class,
所以我们将在下一节课讨论这个，
I keep saying this,
我一直这么说，
but there's so many things to discuss.
但有太多的事情要讨论。
A bunch of these systems will maintain their own disk scheduler or dispatcher,
许多这样的系统将维护它们自己的磁盘调度器，
that decides when what pages to read and what order,
以决定何时读取哪些页面以及读取的顺序，
because, otherwise, if you just go do more of efforts against the OS,
否则，如果你去对操作系统做更多的努力，
the OS is gonna figure out how to order things,
操作系统会找到如何排序的方法，
but again, the, the, the database system is in a better position
但是，再次，数据库系统是更好的地方，
to know what it actually needs and in what order,
了解它需要什么，以及以什么顺序，
so, various systems can can, can have their own thread
所以，各种系统可以有它们自己的线程，
decide how to schedule their own disk reads.
决定如何调度它们自己的磁盘读取。
And you want to do this,
你想这样做，
because you want to minimize the amount of thrashing,
是因为你想要最大限度地减少颠簸的次数，
of bringing things into a memory, how to throw it, throw it out right away.
把东西带入内存，以及如何丢弃它。
So if you know two queries need the same page,
如果两个查询需要相同的页面，
maybe you bring that in first before some other pages
你可能会先将其放在其他页面之前，
and then you you throw away the first page, once you know those two queries are done with it.
然后你丢弃第一个页面，在知道这两个查询完成后。
So the database files are going to be broken up into what call pages,
所以数据库文件将被分解成所谓的页面，
and the database system is responsible for keeping track of
数据系统负责跟踪，
what data has been read and written to these various pages,
哪些数据已被读取和写入这些不同的页面，
and then keeps track of how much space is available in each of them.
然后跟踪每个页面中有多少可用空间。
Because again, if I, if I insert a new, I need to insert a new tuple,
因为，如果我插入一个新的 tuple ，
I need to find a page that has space for me,
我需要找到一个有空间的页面，
so I'll keep track of some directory,
所以，我将跟踪某个目录，
that says this page has this amount of space and go put it in there.
显示这个页面有空间，然后将其放入其中。
Now, the data system itself, the storage manager layer,
现在，数据系统本身，存储管理器层，
the part we're talking about here,
也就是我们在这里讨论的部分，
it's not going to maintain multiple copies of these pages for redundancy replication purposes,
不会出于冗余复制的目的维护这些页面的多个副本，
we assume that's going to happen either both above and below this part of the system in the stack,
我们假设这将在堆栈中系统的这一部分的上方和下方发生，
so above would be like something,
所以，上面就像是某种东西，
something that knows if a query shows up and wants to do a write,
它知道查询是否出现并想要进行写入，
send it to another, another physical box or another node
将其发送到另一个物理盒子或另一个节点，
and have both those machines do the write.
并让这两台机器都正确地执行写入。
And then below it would be like,
然后在下面，它就像是，
if you're running RAID or some kind of storage appliance that knows how to replicate pages,
如果你运行的是 RAID 或某种知道如何复制页面的存储设备，
and then down below, it'll do that as well.
然后在下面，它也会这样做。
Typically, database systems will not maintain multiple copies themselves,
通常，数据库系统本身不会维护多个副本，
because it's a bunch of extra work,
因为这是一大堆额外的工作，
that ideally, you don't want to have to do.
理想情况下，你不会想这么做。
So, what is a page
那么，什么是页面呢，
so in our view, from a data perspective,
在我们看来，从数据的角度来看，
a page is going to be a fixed size block of data
页面是一个固定大小的数据块，
and it can contain data from any part of the database itself,
它可以包含来自数据库本身任何部分的数据，
and for, for this lecture, we assume it's just tuples or records,
对于这节课，我们假设它只有 tuple 或记录，
but it can contain indexes, log information, additional metadata, the catalog statistics, right,
但它可以包含索引，日志信息，附加元数据，目录统计，
it doesn't matter,
这无关紧要，
but it's still going to be broken up into these, these fixed size blocks.
但它仍然会被分解成这些固定大小的块。
Most systems are not going to mix page types,
大多数系统不会混合页面类型，
meaning you don't take a one megabyte page
这意味着你不会使用 1 兆字节，
and put in data from this table and this table and index and stuff like that,
放入这个表和索引等内容的数据，
for simplicity, you're going to assume that one page belongs to some object in the database,
为了简单起见，你将假设一个页面属于数据库中的某个对象，
a table or index and so forth,
表或索引等，
and it would only contain data for that particular object.
并且它只包含特定对象的数据。
Some systems are gonna require every page to be self-contained,
一些系统将要求每个页面都是自包含的，
meaning all the information, all the metadata you need to have
这意味着所有信息、所有元数据，
in order to understand what's inside that page
以便理解页面内部的内容，
has to be included in the page itself.
都必须包含在页面中。
So, Oracle is probably the most famous one that does this, right,
Oracle 可能是做这个的最著名的公司，
so, within a page, you have to keep track of like,
所以，在一个页面中，你必须跟踪，
it belongs to this table and has these columns with these types and so forth.
它属于这个表，以及具有这些类型的列等。
The reason why they want to do this is because,
他们这样做的原因是，
if there's some corruption in, you know, in the database files,
如果数据库文件中有一些损坏，
you don't want to have some page that contains the metadata about the table get blown away
你不希望包含有关表的元数据的某个页面丢失，
and then now you can't understand what's in any other page, right.
然后现在你无法理解任何其他页面中的内容。
Again, replication can can can solve this problem,
复制可以解决这个问题，
hardware has certainly got a lot more reliable in in modern times than it did before,
硬件在现代肯定比以前可靠得多，
like hard drives, super flaky before,
比如硬盘驱动器，以前超级脆弱，
they're still not ideal, but they're much better than they used to be.
它们仍然不理想，但它们比过去好多了。
So maybe having every page be self-contained is less of an issue today,
所以，让每个页面都自包含在今天可能不是什么问题，
but the design choice that Oracle made very early on.
但这是 Oracle 很早就做出的设计选择。
Now, every page in our database file is going to be given a unique identifier,
现在，我们的数据库文件中的每一页都将被赋予一个唯一的标识符，
like a page ID,
比如 page ID ，
like you know, some number 64 bit integer, 32 bit integer,
一些 64 位整数或 32 位整数，
and then there'll be some method or some mechanism, that the database system is going to use,
然后，数据库系统将使用某种方法或某种机制，
that allow it to map a page ID to some physical location on our storage device,
将 page ID 映射到存储设备上的某个物理位置，
and again, that could be like a file name inside of a directory at some offset,
这可能是某个偏移量上一个目录中的文件名，
if we're running on like a cloud storage,
如果我们在云存储上运行，
it could be an S3 bucket at some offset and so forth, right.
它可能是一个 S3 桶，在某个偏移量等。
For that purpose, it doesn't matter,
出于这个目的，这并不重要，
we just have a way to say,
我们只是有一种方法可以说，
if we look at page one, two, three,
如果我们看第一页、第二页、第三页，
there's some method to say, here's where to go find it.
有一些方法可以说，这是找到它的地方。
So now what's sort of confusing in the constant database is that,
所以现在常量数据库中令人困惑的是，
there's three different notions of what a page actually is.
对于页面的实际是什么，有三种不同的概念。
And so at the lowest level, you have what is called a hardware page,
所以在最低层，你有一个所谓的硬件页面，
this is typically 4 kilobytes,
这通常是 4 千字节，
and this is going to be the,
而这将是，
the largest size or the smallest size of a page, a, a block of data,
最大尺寸的数据块，
that the hardware can guarantee that it can do atomic writes,
硬件可以保证其具有原子写入，
so what do I mean by that,
那么我是什么意思，
what do I mean by atomic writes?
我所说的原子写入是什么意思？
He says, all or nothing, right,
他说，全部或没有，正确，
so it means that,
所以，这意味着，
if I tell the hardware I want to write 4 kilobytes
如果我告诉硬件我要写入 4 千字节，
and I get back an acknowledgment, yes, I wrote 4 kilobytes,
然后我得到确认，是的，我写入了 4 千字节，
then I can assume that it made it,
那么，我就可以假设它成功了，
if I need to write 8 kilobytes,
如果我需要写入 8 千字节，
and I send that as two 4 kilobyte blocks down to the OS, to the hardware,
然后我将其作为两个 4 千字节块向下发送到硬件，
I may write the first 4 kilobytes
我可能会写入前 4 千字节，
and then crash and then come back,
然后崩溃，然后回来，
and then the, the second 4 kilobytes didn't make it,
然后，第二个 4 千字节没有成功，
there's no guarantee, the hardware can't guarantee that I can do that all atomically,
硬件不能保证我能在那里以原子方式做到，
all or nothing.
全部或没有。
And so because of this,
正因为如此，
we have to do much other extra stuff inside our database system to deal with that,
我们不得不在数据库系统中做很多其他额外的工作来处理这个，
we'll get to that later.
我们稍后再谈这个。
And then above that, above the hardware,
然后在硬件上面，
now that's going to be, the operating system is going to have its own notion of a page,
操作系统拥有自己的页面概念，
and in Linux, by default, this is 4 kilobytes,
在 Linux 中，默认情况下，这是 4 千字节，
and again, this is like mapping something that's on the hardware to something that's in virtual memory,
这就像是将硬件上的东西映射到虚拟内存中的东西，
now, in, in x64 they also support two different modes,
现在，在 x64 中，它们也支持两种不同的模式，
or huge pages as they're called,
或者所谓的大页面，
so you can get page sizes, actually 2 megabytes and 1 gigabyte,
所以你可以得到页面大小，是 2MB 和 1GB ，
and again, the hardware can't guarantee that it can, it can write out 4 kilobytes atomically
同样，硬件不能保证它原子地写入超过 4 千字节，
is just to reduce the amount of bookkeeping that the OS does
只是为了减少操作系统所做的[记录量]，
for the pages that it brings into memory.
对于从内存中借来的页面。
And then with inside that now above that,
然后，在它的上面，
the database system is going to have its own notion of a page as well, right,
数据库系统也有自己的页面概念，
and typically, this is going to be anywhere in the range of 512, 512 bytes,
通常，这将是 512 字节范围，
this is what SQLite does,
这是 SQLite 所做的，
up to, I think 32 kilobytes,
向上到，我想是 32 千字节，
some systems let you go up to 64 kilobytes, right.
有些系统最高可达 64 千字节。
And so the page size is going to be the way we'll represent,
页面大小是我们表示的方式，
where to find,
在哪里找到，
sorry, the page ID is a way to represent,
抱歉， page ID 是一种表示方式，
at what offset in some file for a given page size,
对于给定的页面大小，在某个文件中的偏移量，
can we find the data that we're looking for.
我们可以找到我们要查找的数据。
So, okay, this said,
所以，好的，这里是说，
most systems are the default is going be 4 kilobytes,
大多数系统的默认大小是 4 千字节，
in SQL Server and Postgres, the the page size is going to be 8 kilobytes,
在 SQL Server 和 Postgres 中，页面大小是 8 千字节，
and then in MySQL, they go up to 16 kilobytes,
然后在 MySQL 中，它们会上升到 16 千字节，
for something like DB2 and enterprises,
对于 DB2 和企业之类的东西，
actually for for DB2, on a per table basis,
实际上对于 DB2 ，在每个表上，
you can change the, the page size.
你可以更改页面大小。
And I take a guess,
我猜一猜，
would anybody take a guess,
有没有人猜一猜，
why one page size, a larger page size,
为什么一个更大的页面尺寸，
might be a better idea?
可能是一个更好的想法？
What did I say in the beginning,
我一开始是怎么说的，
what do we want to try to maximize?
我们想要最大化的是什么？
Sequential access, correct, yes.
顺序访问，正确，是的。
So if I now have, if I'm organizing on disk 16 kilobytes blocks,
所以，如果我在磁盘上组织 16 千字节的块，
and I need to read 16 kilobytes of data,
我需要读取 16 千字节的数据，
then it's one, one call to to our dispatcher, in, in the database system,
然后这是在数据库系统中我们的调度器进行一次调用，
that makes one call into the OS to go grab contiguous sixteen kilobytes,
对操作系统进行一次调用，以获取连续的 16 千字节，
if I'm using four kilobyte pages,
如果我使用 4 千字节的页面，
then I got to make separate calls or do separate lookups
那么我必须进行单独的调用或进行单独的查找，
to go get the data in potentially random locations.
以便在可能随机的位置获取数据。
And there's, there's syscalls you can make to the OS or to, to the device itself,
你可以对操作系统和设备本身进行一些系统调用，
that when you allocate data that you want things to be ideally contigously aligned,
当你分配你想要连续排列的数据时，
you can like pre allocate an extent
你可以预分配一个数据区，
to say allocate me a 10 megabyte block of data
比如给我分配一个 10 兆字节的数据块，
and then then the database system can divide that 10 megabytes block into,
然后数据库系统可以把这 10 兆字节的数据块分成，
you know, 8 kilobytes chunks or whatever block size it wants.
8 千字节块或任何它想要的块大小。
Yes.
是的。
Right, so then he says, and he's correct,
好的，他说的，他是对的，
doesn't this mean that large page sizes make writes more expensive,
这难道不意味着大页面会让写入变得更昂贵吗，
because now if I only have to write 1 kilobyte,
因为现在，如果我只需要写入 1 千字节，
but I'm storing as 16 kilobyte page,
但我存储为 16 千字节页，
I got to write it all 16 kilobytes,
我就必须全部写入 16 千字节，
absolutely yes,
绝对是，
so this is a good point,
所以这是一个很好的观点，
this is something I would say throughout the entire semester,
这是我整个学期都会说的话，
its, I mean, it's not just for databases,
我的意思是那不只是对于数据库，
computer science in general, there's no free lunch,
对于一般的计算机科学，天下没有免费的午餐，
there's pros and cons to each of these
每一种都有利弊，
and different situations, one approach might be better than another,
不同情况下，一种方法可能比另一种更好，
if my workload is entirely readonly,
如果我的工作负载完全是只读的，
if I never write anything,
只要我从来不写任何东西，
then yeah, I want large page sizes,
那么，是的，我想要大的页面大小，
assuming I'm doing large sequential scans,
假设我进行大的顺序扫描，
if I'm doing much of writes, then maybe I want something smaller,
如果我写入很多次，也许我想要更小的东西，
but what the write amount is, depends.
取决于写入的数量是多少。
Yeah, so his statement is,
是的，所以他的说法是，
if I do 16 kilobytes reads
如果我做 16 千字节的读取，
and I'm still using 4 kilobytes of data,
我仍然使用 4 千字节的数据，
assuming that 16 kilobytes is contiguous,
假设 16 千字节是连续的，
then can I go make a, you know, go make a single call
那么我能不能一个调用，
to get 16 kilobytes that are contiguous,
来获得连续的 16 千字节，
and then if I had the write individual, within 4 kilobytes,
然后，如果我在 4 千字节中有写入，
I can still write those out,
我还可以把它们写出，
absolutely, yes,
绝对是的，
and this is what I was saying before,
这就是我之前所说的，
we will then choose algorithms or methods,
然后，我们将选择算法或方法，
that that try to write that data out,
尝试写出该数据，
so that it is contiguous,
它是连续的，
so that we can do those fetches, right.
我们就可以进行这些获取。
And again, this is something a database system can do for us,
同样，这是数据库系统可以为我们做的事情，
because we know what the query is,
因为我们知道查询是什么，
we know what data you're going to potentially read,
我们知道你可能要读取的数据，
and so we can read ahead for you
所以我们可以为你提前读取，
and try to fetch things that are before you actually need them.
尝试在你实际需要之前获取它们。
Now the OS can do that with pre fetching as well,
操作系统也可以使用预先获取来实现这个，
but it can only prefetch things that are contiguous,
但它只能预取连续的内容，
in both directions, I think, in Linux, yes,
我想是在两个方向上，在 Linux 中，是的，
but it can't do, if I have to pre fetch things that aren't contiguous,
但是它不能，如果我必须预先获取不连续的东西，
it can't do that for me.
它不能为我做到这个。
So this is clear.
所以，这个很清楚。
So again there be some page ID
这里还有一些 page ID ，
and we'll see this in a second,
我们马上就会看到，
how this is being used,
它是如何被使用的，
that's going to allow us page page 103,
这将允许我们，第 103 页，
here's where to go find it.
这里是找到它的地方。
All right, so, now we've got to talk about,
好的，所以，现在，我们必须讨论，
how do we actually keep track of that mapping of page IDs to locations,
如何跟踪 page ID 到位置的映射，
and there's, this would be one of the big differences
这将最大区别之一，
of how the database systems are going organize the and their pages.
数据库系统如何组织页面。
And again, there's not, I'm not saying one way is better than another.
再说一次，我不是说一种方式比另一种方式更好。
I'll describe the heap file approach is the most common one,
我将描述，堆文件方法是最常见的方法，
but certainly a bunch of other systems are doing different things,
但当然还有许多其他系统在做不同的事情，
and there are tradeoffs for all these ones.
所有这些都需要权衡取舍。
So at this point,
所以，在这一点上，
where we're in our discussion,
我们正在讨论的地方，
we don't need to know anything about what's inside of our pages,
我们不需要知道任何关于我们的页面内部的内容，
like, again, we don't care whether it's indexes or tuples,
比如，我们不关心它是索引还是 tuple ，
we just need to know,
我们只需要知道，
for a given page, how do I go find it
对于给定的页面，我如何找到它，
and how to keep track of what pages I actually have.
以及如何跟踪我实际拥有的页面。
So tree files is basically,
所以树文件基本上就是，
you store, you can store the,
你存储，你可以存储，
sort of in the leaf nodes, you can store the actual pages themselves
在叶节点中，你可以存储页面本身，
or you can have a hash table.
或者你也可以有哈希表。
ISAM or sequential sorted files,
ISAM 或按顺序排序文件，
this is something from like the 70s,
这是 70 年代的东西，
my sql used to do this by default,
MySQL 默认这样做，
it's not that common anymore,
这不再那么常见了，
but again it's another way to sort of keep track of things.
但这也是另一种跟踪事物的方式。
And then hashing file is going use the hash table to lookups.
然后哈希表文件使用哈希表来查找。
Heap files is going to be the most common one,
堆文件是最常见的一种，
but these other methods exist.
但是这些其他方法是存在的。
And then for the log structure stuff,
然后对于日志结构的内容，
we'll see that next class.
我们将在下一节课看到。
The directory is really keeping track,
目录是在跟踪，
you still want to keep track of where things are,
你仍然想要跟踪东西在哪里，
because we don't care, we don't care what's inside the pages.
因为我们不在乎页面里有什么。
All right, so heap file is going to be a collection of unordered pages,
好的，所以，堆文件是一个无序页面的集合，
where our tuples will be stored in random order,
我们的 tuple 将以随机顺序存储，
and again, the relational model allows us to do that,
关系模型允许我们这样做，
because the relational model doesn't define, doesn't says,
因为关系模型没有定义，
that the data doesn't have to be specified in exact order,
数据不必指定确切的顺序，
some systems might pre sort them,
一些系统可能会为它们预先排序，
to make things faster for other effects,
以使操作更快，为了其他效果，
but the relational model doesn't require you to do that.
但关系模型不要求你这样做。
And so the only API we need in our storage manager to support a heap file is basically,
所以，我们的存储管理器中支持堆文件的唯一 API 基本上是，
to create pages, get a page, write to a page, delete a page,
创建页面、获取页面、写入页面、删除页面，
and then an iterator API,
然后是一个迭代的 API ，
that allows to to sequentially read pages
允许按顺序读取页面，
to get the list of all the page ID that we have
以获得我们拥有的所有 page ID 的列表，
and read over them.
并对它们进行读取。
So, managing this heat file is really easy to do,
所以，管理这个堆文件是很容易的，
if your database is a single file,
如果你的数据库是单个文件，
like in DuckDB or like in, in SQLite, right,
比如在 DuckDB 中或在 SQLite 中。
because all you need to do, to find a given page is
因为要找到给定的页面，
just know what page, the page number is,
只需知道页面编号是多少，
you know what the size of the page is,
你知道页面的大小，
because they all have to be the same size,
因为它们都必须是相同的大小，
and now you just do a simple arithmetic,
现在你只需要做一个简单的算术运算，
like take whatever the ID I'm looking for,
比如取我要找的任何 ID ，
multiply it by the the size of the page
乘以页面的大小，
and then I can jump to whatever that offset is in the file,
然后我就可以跳到文件中的任何偏移量，
and I know exactly what I'm looking for.
我很清楚我在找什么。
And if you go look in the SQLite documentation,
如果你去看 SQLite 的文档，
they, they talk about how,
他们谈到，
in, in the header of their of their data file,
在他们的数据文件的头部中，
all sort of the metadata they keep track of basically do this trick here.
他们跟踪的所有元数据都使用了这个技巧。
Where things get tricky is,
问题变得棘手的是，
if you have multiple files,
如果你有多个文件，
which again, most systems do,
大多数系统都是，
Postgres does, MySQL does, Oracle does.
Postgres 是， MySQL 是， Oracle 是。
And then now we need a way to say
然后现在我们需要一种方法来说明，
for given page number two,
对于给定的第二页，
what file and what offset, what directory, what file, what offset has the page that I need, right.
什么目录，什么文件，什么偏移量有我需要的页面。
And this is what a heap file page directory can get, get for us,
这就是堆文件页目录可以为我们获得的，
again, think of it's like a hash table,
把它想象成一个哈希表，
where you're just keeping track of,
你只是在跟踪，
it's mapping from the page ID to to the pages in the data file.
它是从 page ID 到数据文件中的页面的映射。
And this typically be sort of special file,
这通常是一种特殊的文件，
you have the header of, of the single database file
你有单个数据库文件的头部，
or at some special location inside of the database system and a directory.
或者位于数据库系统和目录内的某个特殊位置。
And you can sort of think it's a database,
你可以把它想象成一个数据库，
when the database, it's the database that keeps track of what's in your database,
它是数据库跟踪数据库中的内容，
the catalog is part of that is too,
目录也是其中的一部分，
but this is like keeping track where the physical location things are.
但这就像是跟踪物理位置的东西。
And so this has to be kept in sync with the actual files on disk,
所以，这必须与磁盘上的实际文件保持同步，
because I don't want to create a bunch of pages,
因为我不想创建一堆页面，
not update my page directory,
没有更新我的页面目录，
I crash and come back,
我崩溃了，然后又回来，
and now my page directory doesn't know about these other pages
现在我的页面目录不知道这些其他页面，
and I can't get to them, right.
我也不能访问它们。
So there's, there's a bunch of extra tricks we have to do
所以，我们必须采取一系列额外的技巧，
to make sure that these things are kept in sync.
为了确保这些东西保持同步。
Okay, so just thinking like I have a bunch of pages,
好的，所以考虑我有一大堆页面，
they're some, they're on some location, a bunch of files, doesn't matter where,
它们在某个位置，一堆文件，在哪里并不重要，
and then it's just a mapping
然后它只是一个映射，
to tell me where to go find it.
告诉我去哪里找它。
Additional metada we keep track of,
我们跟踪的其他元数据，
like for every single page, we can keep track of an [essential] location,
比如每一个页面，我们可以跟踪一个重要的位置，
the number of free slots that they actually have,
它们实际拥有的空闲空间的数量，
or free space they have,
或者他们拥有的空闲空间，
so now if I want to insert a tuple
现在，如果我想要插入一个 tuple ，
and I got to find a page to put it in,
我必须找到一个页面来放入它，
I don't want to have to scan them all
我不想必须扫描所有的页面，
and figure out who's got free space,
并计算出谁有空闲空间，
my page directory would tell me that, right.
我的页面目录会告诉我这个。
And then if I run out of pages,
然后，如果我用完了页面，
I know how to allocate them
我知道如何分配它们，
and then update my page directory to point this as well.
然后更新我的页面目录以指出这里。
Again, just think, think of a hash table that get written to disk,
只是想想一个写入磁盘的哈希表，
that keeps track of the pages that I have,
它跟踪我拥有的页面，
but then I can also iterate or scan through and say,
但我也可以迭代或扫描，然后说，
here's page one, here's page two, here's page three,
这是第一页，这是第二页，这是第三页，
because we're going to need this,
因为我们需要这个，
if we have an access method like a sequential scan operator,
如果我们有一种访问方法，比如顺序扫描操作符，
if we don't have an index,
如果我们没有索引，
we need to be able to iterate over every single tuple on the table.
我们需要能够迭代表中的每个 tuple 。
So the page directory needs to be exposed as that, that API.
所以页面目录需要公开为那个 API 。
Yes.
是的。
Yeah, so his question is,
是的，所以他的问题是，
because the directory has to be brought in a memory in order to read it,
因为目录必须被带入内存才能读取，
it's, it's a non-volatile memory,
它是一个非易失性内存，
so now if I crash, I don't want to lose it,
所以现在如果我崩溃了，我不想失去它，
does that mean any changes I make to it have to be written a disk.
这是否意味着我对它所做的任何更改都必须写入磁盘。
Yes.
是的。
But like, but it's not as bad as,
但是，这并没有那么糟糕，
like you're not updating this thing all the time, right,
你不是一直在更新东西，
so you're not going to,
所以你不会，
you know, if you run out of space in your, in your database file
如果你的数据库文件中的空间用完了，
and allocate more pages,
并分配了更多的页面，
you're not going to allocate just one page, right,
你不会只分配一个页面，
because then you can potentially you do that for every single query,
因为这样你就可能对每个查询执行此操作，
you allocate like you know a gigabyte of data,
你分配 1 吉字节的数据，
update your page directory that gets written to disk,
更新写入磁盘的页面目录，
once you make sure that's persisted and it's safe,
在确保被持久保存且安全之后，
then you proceed with running the query.
然后继续运行查询。
Yes, so statement, any update to the page of directory has to be written a disk,
是的，所以，任何对目录页面的更新必须写入磁盘，
absolutely yes,
完全正确，
because otherwise you don't know what, you don't know what you have.
因为否则你不知道你有什么。
Yes.
是的。
This question is,
问题是，
is this sort in a special database file or does it sort along with other pages,
这种排序是在特殊的数据库文件中还是与其他页面一起排序，
what do you might special,
你说的特殊是什么意思，
just like a separate file,
就像一个单独的文件，
yeah, so in some systems, will as a separate file,
是的，在某些系统中，会作为一个单独的文件，
SQLite will store this in the header of the file,
SQLite 会将其存储在文件的头部中，
typically stored separately.
通常是单独存储。
So his question is,
所以他的问题是，
when I say a database system could use multiple files,
当我说一个数据系统可以使用多个文件时，
I mean within one table, does it contain multiple files
我是指在一个表中，它包含多个文件，
or within the databases, contain multiple files.
还是在数据库中，包含多个文件。
Anyone?
有人知道吗？
Yeah, so DuckDB uses one file, all the table,
是的， DuckDB 使用一个文件，对于所有表格，
same as SQLite,
SQLite 也是，
but I mean,
但我的意思是，
we can pop up at Postgres and look in the data directory,
我们可以弹出 Postgres 并查看数据目录，
there's a bunch of files in there,
里面有一堆文件，
that have numbers in them,
里面有数字，
and there various data files
各种各样的数据文件，
and sometimes there'll be for indexes,
有时是索引，
sometimes there'll be for tables.
有时是表。
And various systems do different things
不同的系统做不同的事情，
and again not, to keep repeating myself,
不断地重复我自己，
this is the beauty of SQL,
这就是 SQL 的美妙之处，
I don't know, don't care,
我不知道，我不在乎，
in MySQL queries, whether I have one file or a thousand files,
在 MySQL 查询中，我是有一个文件还是一千个文件，
the database system can decide how to do that,
数据库系统可以决定如何做到，
it just knows how to run your query for you.
它知道如何为你运行查询。
So again, different database systems do different things.
所以，不同的数据库系统做不同的事情。
His question is,
他的问题是，
how do you know whether you want to use multiple files for for one table,
如何知道是否要为一个表使用多个文件，
again, it depends,
同样，这要视情况而定，
so like if we won't talk about large, large columns yet,
所以如果我们还不讨论[大列]，
but like see say you have a, you have a table,
但是比如你有一个表，
that has a BLOB field or a TEXT field,
它有一个 BLOB 字段或一个 TEXT 字段，
and that's like 10 megabytes,
大约有 10 兆字节，
you'd want to store that in separate pages,
你可能希望将其存储在单独的页面中，
but maybe you want to store that compressed,
但可能需要将其压缩存储，
because it's a bunch of text data,
因为它是一堆文本数据，
so you have the regular columns of the integers and floats, whatever,
所以你有常规的整型和浮点型列，
that stored in one file,
存储在一个文件中，
and then your large stuff is stored in another file, right.
然后你的大件东西存储在另一个文件中。
So that's one approach,
所以这是一种方法，
but you can imagine also too,
但是你也可以想象，
maybe you just, you just, you have some space in a single file,
也许你只是，你在一个单独的文件中有一些空间，
at the top parts of the fixed stuff, the bottom of the [],
在固定[东西]的顶部，[]的底部，
it depends.
视情况而定。
I think MySQL up to 5.6 used to store,
我想 MySQL 直到 5.6 使用存储，
I think it was one file for all tables or all databases,
我想它使用一个文件对于所有表或者所有数据库，
and they don't,
他们没有，
no, it was one file per database
不，每个数据库一个文件，
and they split it up to be one file, not per table,
他们把它分成一个文件，而不是每个表，
and separate files for indexes.
以及单独的对于索引的文件。
Okay.
好的。
So now we know roughly at what the files look like,
所以，现在我们大致了解了文件的外观，
or how the files are laid out
文件的布局，
and how we keep track of where they exist.
以及我们如何跟踪它们的存在位置。
So, let's talk about what's actually inside the pages themselves.
所以，让我们讨论一下页面本身的内容。
So every page is going to have a header,
所以每个页面都会有一个 header ，
that's going to tell you something about what the data actually is.
这将告诉你一些关于数据实际是什么的信息。
So a common thing would be like the page size or like a checksum, right,
所以，常见的东西应该是页面大小或校验和，
so if you crash and come back or you restart the system,
所以，如果你崩溃并回来或重新启动系统，
or actually anytime you fetch something from disk,
或者任何时候你从磁盘获取东西，
you compute a fast checksum to make sure that the data isn't corrupted.
你都会计算快速校验和以确保数据没有损坏。
Maybe keep track of the version of the database system that actually created the the page,
也许可以跟踪创建页面的数据库系统的版本，
that way you put out a new version that breaks compatibility,
你推出了一个破坏兼容性的新版本，
you can have some code that knows how to read the old data.
你有一些代码，知道如何读取旧数据。
We won't talk about transactions until after the midterm,
我们不会谈论事务，直到期中考试之后，
but like, you can keep track of
但是，你可以跟踪，
like what thread or what transaction wrote to what data in this
什么线程或什么事务写到这个文件中的什么数据，
and whether it's actually visible to whatever, whatever query you're running.
以及它是否对你正在运行的查询是可见的。
If the data is compressed,
如果数据被压缩，
or encoded in a certain way,
或者以某种方式进行编码，
which we'll discuss next week,
我们将在下周讨论，
there'll be metadata about how what the compression scheme actually is.
将会有关于压缩方案的实际情况的元数据。
To be information about what the the schema is or what the table schema is,
为了提供关于模式是什么或表模式是什么的信息，
as we talk about Oracle does.
在我们讨论 Oracle 时。
Sometimes there's additional statistics,
有时还会有附加统计信息，
about what's in the data itself,
关于数据中有什么，
so like for a given column,
比如，对于给定列，
what's the min, the min value and the max value,
最小值和最大值是什么，
because maybe I just need to read that,
因为也许我只需要读取它，
instead of actually reading the data to figure out whether and there's something I need, right.
而不是真正地读取数据来找出是否有我需要的东西。
And again, as we already discussed,
正如我们已经讨论过的，
Oracle is famously self-contained,
Oracle 以自包含而闻名，
but not all systems do that.
但并不是所有的系统都这样做的。
So now, within the page itself,
所以，现在，在页面本身内，
we need to decide how we actually want to organize the tuple data, right.
我们需要决定我们想要如何组织 tuple 数据。
So at this point in this lecture,
所以在这节课的这一点上，
we're going to assume that we're only storing tuples in our pages,
我们将假设我们只在页面中存储 tuple ，
we'll discuss indexes later,
我们稍后将讨论索引，
and then we're going to assume that we're storing tuples in a row-oriented manner,
然后我们将假设以面向行的方式存储 tuple ，
meaning like,
意思是，
if I have five attributes, I will have, I will have a tuple
如果我有五个属性，我会有一个 tuple ，
and I'll have those five attributes contiguously,
我会有这五个属性是连续的，
before I see the next tuple.
在我看到下一个 tuple 之前。
Next week we'll see about column stores,
下周我们将看看列存储，
we store this slightly different,
我们存储这个略有不同，
but for our purposes here,
但出于我们的目的，
we assume that's row-oriented
我们假设它是面向行的，
and we'll break this next week.
我们将在下周讨论这个问题。
So there's three different approaches,
所以有三种不同的方法，
what, what it could actually be in our pages.
它在我们的页面上可能是什么。
So the tuple-oriented storage,
在面向 tuple 的存储中，
where we're only storing tuples and the exact values that those tuples have.
我们只存储 tuple 和 tuple 拥有的值。
There be a log-structured approach,
这是一种日志结构方法，
where we just store deltas of what changed since the last time, last time these tuple was updated.
我们只存储上次 tuple 更新以来更改的增量。
And that should be index-organized,
然后是面向索引的，
index-organized storage to be,
面向索引的存储是，
it could be like a tree structure,
它类似于树结构，
where in the leaf nodes, I'm actually storing the data itself.
在叶节点中，存储了数据本身。
So today's lecture, we're only going to talk about the first one,
所以今天的课程，我们只会讨论第一个，
tuple-oriented storage,
面向 tuple 的存储，
and then next week we'll talk about the two other approaches.
下周我们会讨论另外两种方法。
All right, so let's think about,
好的，让我们考虑一下，
how do we actually want to store tuples in our pages, right.
我们想要如何在我们的页面中存储 tuple 。
So let's say we have a really simple approach,
让我们假设我们有一个非常简单的方法，
where in our page header,
在我们的页面 header 中，
we just keep track of the number of tuples that we have, right,
我们只跟踪我们拥有的 tuple 的数量，
and anytime we want to insert a new tuple,
任何时候我们想插入一个新的 tuple ，
we just append to the end, right.
我们只是追加到末尾。
So we can assume our data fixed length,
所以我们可以假设我们的数据是固定长度的，
so if I want to insert a new tuple,
所以，如果我想插入一个新的 tuple ，
I just go look at the header,
我只需查看 header ，
see the number tuples,
查看 tuple 的数量，
multiply that by the size of the tuple
乘以 tuple 的大小，
and that tells me where offset I want to write the page.
这就告诉我我想要写入页面的偏移量。
What's wrong,
怎么了，
oh, lantern fly, just kill it,
哦，苍蝇，杀了它吧，
is anybody want to keep that alive,
有人想要它活着吗，
for those on Youtube, we have a lantern fly infestation.
对于 Youtube 上的人，我们有苍蝇出没。
All right, all right, so, is this a good idea or a bad idea,
好的，所以，这是个好主意还是坏主意，
I said strawman,
我说的是 strawman ，
so it's obviously a bad idea,
所以这显然是个坏主意，
why is it a bad idea?
为什么这是个坏主意？
Right, so if I deleted tuples,
是的，所以如果我删除 tuple ，
I delete tuple 2,
我删除 tuple 2 ，
it throws everything out of order, right,
它把所有的东西都打乱了，
because now, I what I want to be able to do is insert a new tuple
因为现在我想要做的是插入一个新的 tuple ，
and I won't put at the end,
我不会把它放在最后，
I want to use this spot here, right,
我想用这里的位置，
so, you know, number tuples is enough,
所以， tuple 的数量是足够的，
maybe I keep track of where things are located,
也许我会记着东西放在哪里，
second side, where to put them in, right.
第二方面，把它们放在哪里。
But, you know, it's going beyond what I'm showing here.
但是，它超出了我在这里展示的范围。
What's another obvious problem?
另一个明显的问题是什么？
He said what if one of the tuple too big to start on the page.
他说，如果一个 tuple 太大，不能在页面上开始。
Yes, but also what if they're not the fixed length,
是的，但如果它们不是固定长度，
which most data is, is not fixed length, right,
大多数数据都是，不是固定长度，
email addresses aren't the same size,
电子邮件地址大小不同，
Andrew IDs aren't the same, always the same size.
Andrew ID 并不相同，几乎总是相同的大小。
Now I can just sort as a [char] type,
现在我可以作为[char]类型进行排序，
but what does that do,
但这会做什么，
that pre allocates the space I need,
预先分配我所需的空间，
and you know, if the largest email address is is 1 kilobyte,
如果最大的电子邮件地址是 1 千字节，
then I have to store 1 kilobyte for every single email address,
那么我必须为每个电子邮件地址存储 1 千字节，
even though it's not going to be using that space, right,
即使它不会使用这个空间，
then, his comment is,
他的评论是，
well, what if the table, can the table can't fit in this page,
如果表不能放在一个页面怎么办，
how do I split in multiple pages.
如何拆分到多个页面中。
We discuss that next week,
我们下周将讨论这个，
but this also would not work, right.
但这也不会奏效。
So clearly, you know, this is not enough for us,
所以很明显，这对我们来说是不够的，
we need additional metadata to keep track of,
我们需要额外的元数据来跟踪，
keep track of how we going to store this,
跟踪我们将如何存储这些内容，
another problem too is like,
另一个问题是，
again, if four, if four could go here, right,
如果 #4 去了这里，
I could fill the gap, where, when I deleted two,
我可以填充删除 #2 时的空隙，
if four needs to go here, then I'm wasting space,
如果 #4 要到这里（#3 下面），那我就是在浪费空间，
but if I want to, maybe move #3 up,
但是也许我可以把 #3 往上移，
but now I have to tell the rest of the system, that I moved three, right,
但现在我必须告诉系统的其余部分，我移动了 #3 ，
because I have told you how I'm pointing to three, how I find three,
因为我已经告诉过你们我是如何指向 #3 的，如何找到 #3 ，
but assuming it's going to be like some offset within this page,
假设这一页中会有一些偏移量，
but now if I'm moving three,
但是现在如果我移动 #3 ，
then, then I have to go update every possible index,
然后我就得去更新所有可能的索引，
that is maybe pointing to it.
那些指向它的（索引）。
And that's going to be super expensive.
这将是非常昂贵的。
So the most common approach to handle this problem is called slotted pages,
所以，处理这个问题的最常见方法称为插槽页面，
and what I'll describe here isn't, you know, isn't going to be exactly how every system does this,
我在这里描述的并不是每个系统是如何做到这一点的，
but at a high level, this is what everyone is doing,
但从更高的层面来看，这就是每个系统都在做的事情，
if you're a row oriented database system,
如果你是一个面向行的数据库系统，
that's using two oriented pages, so not log structured,
它使用面向 tuple 的页面，不是日志结构，
then they're doing something that looks like this.
然后他们在做一些看起来像这样的事情。
So we're going to have, we'll have a header,
所以我们会有一个 header ，
that keeps track of all the metadata, we talked about before,
跟踪我们讨论过的所有的元数据，
but then after the header, we'll have this slot array,
但在 header 之后，我们有这个 slot array ，
where the, at every position in that slot array
在 slot array 中的每个位置，
is going to point to some tuple in our page,
将指向我们页面中的一些 tuple ，
and the tuples will be starting at the bottom, at the end of the page, right,
tuple 将从页面末尾开始，
so at the bottom, we'll have all the fixed length and var-length tuple data,
所以在底部，我们会有固定长度和可变长度的 tuple 数据，
for now, assume that that everything is put together, right,
现在，假设一切都放在一起，
so meaning like, there isn't,
所以意思是，这里没有，
if you have a really large value,
如果你有一个非常大的值，
it isn't stored in separate page,
它不会存储在单独的页面中，
the entire table has to be stored inside this page.
整个表必须存储在这个页面中。
And so the slot array is just going to be storing fixed length offsets
所以， slot arry 将存储固定长度的偏移量，
to where to find the starting location of individual tuples.
以找到单个 tuple 的起始位置，
And maybe you could also store the size of the tuple and the header,
也许你也可以存储 tuple 的大小和 header ，
if you wanted to, right.
如果你愿意的话。
So now what's going to happen is,
所以现在要发生的事情是，
as we need to update the the the table
我们需要更新表，
and add new pages,
并添加新页面，
sorry, add new tuples inside the page,
抱歉，在页面内添加新的 tuple ，
the slot array is going to grow from the beginning to the end,
slot array 将从头到尾增长，
and then all our tuple data is going to grow from the end to the beginning.
然后我们所有的 tuple 数据都将从尾到头增长。
And any single time, I add a new entry in, to my slot array, sorry, new tuple,
每当我添加新的 tuple 时，对于我的 slot array ，
I put, I update the slot array
我都会更新 slot array ，
to tell me where to go find it, right.
告诉我在哪里可以找到它。
So now if I go back to the problem I had before,
现在回到我之前的问题，
where I say I deleted tuple three,
我说我删除了 tuple #3 ，
well, this is fine,
好的，这是可以的，
because I didn't move any other tuples,
因为我没有移动任何其他 tuple ，
the slot array still, for four still points to it,
slot array 的 #4 仍然指向它，
so I don't tell any other part of the system that, I moved four, right.
所以我不用告诉系统的任何其他部分，我移动了 #4 。
But even, you know, if I now wanted to reclaim this space,
但是，如果我现在想要收回这个空间，
that three used to be and I deleted,
#3 曾经拥有的，我删除了的，
if I want to slide three or four over to, to take, you know, compact it,
如果我想把 #4 滑动到，压缩它，
all they need to do now is
他们现在需要做的就是，
update the slot array to point to the new offset,
更新 slot array ，指向新的偏移量，
which is easy to do,
这很容易做到，
I don't have to,
我没必要这么做，
again, relational model says they don't have to do this,
关系模型说他们不必这样做，
some, some systems do, some systems don't,
有些系统做了，有些系统没有，
we'll see this in a second, right,
我们很快就会看到这一点，
and this is all fine.
这一切都很好。
So this is what SQLite, actually I don't know SQLite does this,
这就是 SQLite ，实际上我不知道 SQLite 做了这个，
but what Postgres does,
但这是 Postgres 所做的，
MySQL does, MySQL doesn't do this,
MySQL 所做， MySQL 没有这样做，
SQL Server does this,
SQL Server 是这样做的，
this slotted pages is the most common approach,
这个插槽页面页面是最常见的方法，
this is what everyone does.
这是每个系统都会做的。
Yes.
是的。
So his question is,
所以，他的问题是，
can I reuse slot position three,
我可以重复使用插槽位置 #3 吗，
if I insert a new tuple, yes,
如果我插入一个新的 tuple ，是的，
but I don't have to put that in front of four, right,
但我没必要把这个放在 #4 前面，
I can put it anywhere.
我可以把它放在任何地方。
Other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
Yes.
是的。
Yeah, so her statement, her question is,
是的，所以她的陈述，她的问题是，
wouldn't this be wasting space, if the tuples are variable length,
如果 tuple 是长度可变的，这不是在浪费空间吗，
yeah, so the,
是的，所以，
again, my tuples are growing from the, from, from the,
我的 tuple 是从[]开始增长的，
tuple data is going from the end to the beginning,
tuple 数据是从尾到头的，
slot array is going from the beginning to the end,
slot array 是从头到尾的，
at some point, I'm going to run out of space
在每个时间，我会用完空间，
and there might be a little bit of,
可能会有一点，
you know, little space in the middle that I can't use for anything,
中间的一点空间我不能用来做任何事情，
is that wasted, yes.
这是浪费吗，是的。
But the advantage we get of
但我们获得的优势是，
not having to update other things anytime we shuffle the order the slot array,
不必更新其他东西，当我们重新排序 slot array 时，
is worth that cost.
成本是值得的。
Okay.
好的。
So now, assuming we sort of thinking the slotted pages,
所以现在，假设我们考虑插槽页面，
now we need a way to identify tuples.
现在我们需要一种方法来识别 tuple 。
And this this one, we're going to use the notion of a record ID,
这一次，我们将使用 record ID 的概念，
different data systems may call this the row ID or the row number,
不同的数据系统可能会将其称为 row ID 或 row number ，
but a high level, the way to think about it,
但是一种更高层次的思考方式，
it is a way to uniquely identify some logical tuple,
这是一种唯一识别逻辑 tuple 的方式，
based on its physical location inside of a file inside of a page,
基于其在页面内文件中的物理位置，
and it's typically going to be a combination of a file number, an ID number, the page number,
它通常是文件编号， ID 编号，页面编号的组合，
and then the slot number that corresponds where they exist in that slot array.
然后是对应于它们在 slot array 中存在的位置的 slot 编号。
So that when you want to do a lookup
所以当你想查找一下，
to say I need, I need this tuple,
比如我需要这个 tuple ，
if you have the record ID,
如果你有 record ID ，
you would then look in the page directory
你可以查看页面目录，
and to figure out what page has it,
找出那个页面包含它，
go grab that page,
然后获取那个页面，
then use the slot number inside the slot array
然后使用 slot array 内的 slot 编号，
to figure out where you know what what offset inside that page has the data you're looking for.
找出你要查找的数据在页面内的偏移量。
So most databases will not store this record ID,
所以大多数数据库不会存储这个 record ID ，
this is something that's synthesized, materialize,
这是一个合成的，具体化的东西，
again, based on the page directory you know of, of
基于页面目录，
or how how you keep track of how to find things,
或者跟踪如何找到东西，
meaning, like within the tuple data itself, I'm not storing this record ID.
意思是，在 tuple 数据本身中，我没有存储这个 record ID 。
SQLite does store this as a separate column,
SQLite 确实将它存储为一个单独的列，
that you're not supposed to see, but you can get to it,
你不应该看到它，但你可以访问它，
and the way they do, the reason why they do this is,
而他们这样做的原因是，
because this is how they're going to,
因为这是他们要，
they're going to use this, use this as the primary key
他们要使用这个作为主键，
to allow them to identify individual tuples.
以允许他们识别单独的 tuple 。
So if like I, we, we haven't talked about secondary indexes,
所以，如果，我们还没有讨论过二级索引，
but I have, if I have an index,
如果我有一个索引，
that's not the primary key index,
那不是主键索引，
my, my value, when I, when I do my lookup on a key, is going to be that row ID,
当我查找一个键时，我的值将是那个 row ID ，
which I then use in the primary key row ID index to find the data I need.
然后我使用主键 row ID 索引来查找我需要的数据。
Different systems do different things.
不同的系统做不同的事情。
So, the size of this is going to vary, based on implementation,
这个的大小根据实现的不同而不同，
so Postgres is going to be 6, 6 bytes,
Postgres 是 6 个字节，
SQLite going be 8 bytes or 64 bits,
SQLite 是 8 个字节或 64 位，
SQL Server has an 8 byte []
SQL Server 有 8 字节，
and then Oracle has a 10 byte record ID.
然后 Oracle 有一个 10 字节的 record ID 。
Again, you can see this directly in the database system,
你可以在数据库系统中直接看到这一点，
so we can do a quick demo
所以我们可以做一个快速演示，
just to show you all this.
来向你展示所有这些。
So you're not supposed to use this in your application, right,
所以你不应该在你的应用程序中使用这个，
so even though this would uniquely identify a, a tuple,
尽管这将唯一地识别一个 tuple ，
again, it's the physical location of it,
但这是它的物理位置，
and it could change,
而且它可能会改变，
meaning, like if I insert a tuple
意思是，比如我插入一个 tuple ，
and I get a record ID,
我得到一个 record ID ，
if my application then references it,
如果我的应用程序引用了它，
the problem could be,
问题可能是，
like I could run compaction or garbage collection,
比如我可以运行压缩或垃圾回收，
in Postgres, it's called the Vacuum,
在 Postgres 中，这被称为 Vacuum ，
where I could reorganize that page,
我可以在其中重新组织页面，
where maybe now the slot number changes or the page number changes,
现在可能会更改 slog 编号或页面编号，
and now the thing I'm looking for isn't there anymore.
现在我要找的东西已经不在那里了。
So again, this is a physical aspect of the database system,
所以，这是数据库系统的一个物理方面，
that we're not supposed to really use in our application,
我们不应该在我们的应用程序中使用它，
but it's exposed to us,
但它对我们是公开的，
because if we need to administer and maintain these systems,
因为如果我们需要管理和维护这些系统，
we need to know where the data actually is.
我们需要知道数据实际在哪里。
So let me log in quickly, sorry,
所以让我快速登录，抱歉，
I may need to reconnect.
我可能需要重新连接。
All right, so I do Postgres first.
好的，我先做 Postgres 。
So we're going to create a really simple table r,
所以我们要创建一个非常简单的表 r ，
that just has three tuples, right, 100 101 102.
它只有三个 tuple ， 100 101 102 。
So Postgres has something called the ctid,
所以， Postgres 有一种叫做 ctid 的东西，
and this is going to be a tuple now,
现在，这将是一个 tuple ，
that's going to give you the page number and then the slot number,
它将给你页面编号，然后是 slot 编号，
so these tuple here are at page 0, slot 1, slot 2, slot 3, right.
所以，这些 tuple 在页面 0 ，插槽 1 ，插槽 2 ，插槽 3 ，
So now if I, say I delete the second tuple, I delete 101,
所以现在，如果我删除第二个 tuple ，我删除 101 ，
now when I do my scan again,
现在当我再次扫描的时候，
now you can see that, Postgres [] deleted the tuple,
现在你可以看到， Postgres 删除了那个 tuple ，
but it didn't move things around,
但它并没有移动东西，
and let the data where actually where it actually lives.
并让数据位于其实际存储的位置。
But I can run garbage, the garbage collection,
但我可以运行垃圾收集，
let me insert a tuple back,
让我再插入一个 tuple ，
so I insert 103,
所以我插入 103 ，
now you can see again,
现在你可以再次看到，
it didn't take that that that (0 2) slot,
它没有使用那个 (0,2) 插槽，
from the first tuple I deleted,
从我删除的第一个 tuple 那里，
it is appended to the end, put it in slot 4, right.
它被附加到末尾，放在插槽 4 中。
So then I can now run the,
那么我现在可以运行，
again, in Postgres, it's called the Vacuum,
在 Postgres 中，它被称为 Vacuum ，
so the command is VACUUM,
所以命令是 VACUUM ，
again, this is a Postgres idiom,
这是 Postgres 的习语，
so VACUUM FULL is going to
所以 VACUMM FULL 基本上就是，
have Postgres basically compact every single page and write out a new page, new files,
让 Postgres 压缩每个页面，写出新的页面，新的文件，
so I I have a bunch of pages that are empty,
所以我有一大堆空白的页面，
it'll release them, when it creates a new version.
它将在创建新版本时释放它们。
So now when I do that same query before, right,
所以现在，当我以前做同样的查询时，
now, you see it compact of it, right, (0,1) (0 2) (0 3).
现在，你看到它的压缩， (0,1) (0,2) (0,3) 。
Makes sense, yes.
能理解吗，是的。
So is this the ctid referring to the?
那么这个 ctid 指的是？
Page number and offset, slot number.
页码和偏移量，插槽编号。
Is in the slot array,
位于 slot array 中，
because if you use the slot array
因为如果您使用 slot array ，
to say what offset within the page, do I find what I need.
表示我找到我需要的内容在页面中的偏移量。
Yes.
是的。
The question is,
问题是，
the slot array starts at zero index,
slot array 从 0 索引开始，
even though the page zero index,
即使页面 0 索引，
sorry, slot array starts at one index,
抱歉， slot array 从 1 索引开始，
page starts at zero index,
页面从 0 索引开始，
is there something in, in one,
有什么东西在 1 里面吗，
let's find out,
让我们来看一下，
so you're not supposed to do this,
所以你不应该这么做，
but you can do,
但你可以这么做，
you can actually query this,
你实际上可以查询这个，
ctid equals then (0 0),
ctid = '(0,0)'
doesn't have anything there,
里面什么都没有，
but I can get the other one,
但我可以拿到另一个，
so I don't know why they do that.
所以我不知道他们为什么这么做。
Yes.
是的。
The statement is when we say a slot,
问题是，当我们说一个 slot 时，
the ctid is going to be six bytes,
ctid 将是 6 个字节，
so it's probably a four byte page number and then a two byte offset,
所以它可能是一个 4 字节的页面编号，然后是 2 个字节的偏移量，
doesn't that limit the number of slots we can have in a page,
这不是限制了我们在一个页面中可以拥有的插槽数量吗，
yes, but Postgres is by default is 8 kilobytes page sizes,
是的， Postgres 的默认页面大小是 8 千字节，
so you can't have a billion tuples in a single page.
所以你不能在一个页面中有 10 亿个 tuple 。
All right, so let's look at other systems.
好的，让我们来看看其他系统。
So again, SQlite is, is different,
所以， SQLite 是不同的，
so SQLite, they have this rowid
SQLite 有这个 rowid ，
again and it's actually storing this,
它实际上会存储这个，
it's a 64 bit,
这是 64 位，
it actually stores this,
它实际上存储了这个，
so it uses this as the primary key.
它使用这个作为主键。
Question is,
问题是，
the size of the tuple will sort somewhere,
tuple 的大小会在某个地方，
typically in the header of the tuple, yes.
通常是在 tuple 的 header 中，是的。
All right, so if we delete from,
好的，所以，如果我们删除，
we delete a tuple,
我们删除一个 tuple ，
run the same query,
运行相同的查询，
it doesn't reuse the rowid,
它不会重用 rowid ，
because it's actually a physical thing, the primary key.
因为它实际上是一个物理的东西，主键。
All right, so let's do now, SQL Server,
好的，我们现在做 SQL Server ，
so SQL Server has this different syntax,
所以 SQL Server 有这个不同的语法，
it has this double,
它有一个双重，
that's hard to see,
它很难看到，
if I highlight, I can see it,
如果我高亮显示，我可以看到它，
no, there's two, there's percent signs there, trust me,
不能，这里有两个百分号，相信我，
sorry, let's go back,
抱歉，让我们回去，
there you go, there you go,
这就对了，这就对了，
there's percent signs, sorry,
这里有百分号，抱歉，
so when you run this,
所以当你运行这个的时候，
you get back some hex data like this, right,
你会得到一些像这样的十六进制数据，
what does this mean,
这是什么意思，
so there is an undocumented command,
所以有一个未经记录的命令，
actually, this is all you're not supposed to do this, you can't,
这是你不该做的事，你不能，
it's not documented,
它是无记录的，
meaning Microsoft doesn't officially support this,
这意味着微软不正式支持它，
but there's a command called, whatever, this function here,
但这里有一个命令叫做，就是这个函数，
and you pass in the physical location,
你可以传递物理位置，
and then you'll get back now,
然后，你现在将得到，
the formatted file number, the page number, and then the slot number, right.
格式化的文件编号，页面编号，然后是插槽编号。
And you can actually,
你可以，
it's interesting in learned this today,
今天学到这个很有趣，
you can actually get back what the that function is actually doing,
你可以找回那个函数的实际功能，
so you can get it to spit back the what it actually does,
所以你可以让它输出它的实际功能，
and you see they're taking that physical location
你可以看到它们获取物理位置，
and how they're jumping to different bytes
以及它们如何跳转到不同的字节，
to get the page ID, file number and the slot number.
以获取页面 ID ，文件编号和插槽编号。
So let's do the same thing we did before,
所以，让我们做之前做过的同样的事情，
let's delete 101,
我们删除 101 ，
then we run the same query,
然后我们运行相同的查询，
to get the page number offsets, right,
以获得页码偏移量，
so in this case here, it didn't move anything, right.
所以在这种情况下，它没有移动任何东西。
So now if we insert our tuple back, insert a new tuple,
所以现在如果插入一个新的 tuple ，
run that same query,
运行相同的查询，
now look what it did.
现在看看它做了什么。
So my tuple before with id 102, that was at slot 2,
当我的 id 为 102 的 tuple ，之前在 slot 2 中，
but when I inserted the new tuple,
但当我插入新的 tuple 时，
it moved that second tuple 102 into slot 2,
它把第二个 tuple 102 移动到 slot 2 中，
and then put the new tuple into slot 3,
然后把新的 tuple 放入 slot 3 中，
Postgres didn't do that, right,
Postgres 没有这么做，
Postgres just kept appending on the end,
Postgres 只是追加到末尾，
is this wrong, who knows,
这是错的吗，谁知道呢，
is it better, who knows, right.
这是更好的吗，谁知道呢，
And the reason why you can do this is because,
之所以可以这样做是因为，
when you fetch a page and bring it into memory
因为当你获取一个页面并将其放入内存时，
and you start, you know, inserting a tuple into it,
你开始向其中插入一个 tuple ，
you're holding the latch or the lock on that page,
你就持有了那个页面上的锁，
the database to decide whether it wants to do compaction or whatever the optimization wants to do,
数据库决定它是否想要进行压缩或任何优化想要做的事情，
because it knows that no other thread can write to that page at the same time,
因为它知道没有其他线程可以同时写入那个页面，
so we can decide whether or not, we want, we want to, you know, compact it or not,
所以我们可以决定我们是否想要压缩它，
as we do it,
当我们做的时候，
Postgres doesn't do it, SQL, SQL Server does.
Postgres 没有做， SQL Server 做了。
All right, let's look at everyone's favorite, Oracle.
好的，让我们来看看大家最喜欢的 Oracle 。
I need to create the table first, I think,
我想，我需要先创建一张表，
I don't think it's gonna, let me do that, no, it did,
我不认为它会，让我来做，不，它做了，
so in Oracle, they have a rowid, right,
所以，在 Oracle 中，他们有一个 rowid ，
but you get again some binary data here, right,
但是你在这里又得到了一些二进制数据，
and again, this is stack overflow, this is not me,
这是来自 stack overflow ，不是我，
but there's a bunch of functions you can do,
但这里你可以做很多函数，
run this
运行这个，
and you see now they're storing an OBJID, a FILENUM,
你可以看到它们存储的是 OBJID FILENUM ，
a BLOKCNUM or the page number,
BLOCKNUM 或页面编号，
and then the row slot.
然后是 ROWSLOT 。
So again, this is something taking something that's defined in the textbook,
再说一次，这是在教科书中定义的东西，
describing at like a logical level or describing a theoretical level,
在逻辑层面或理论层面上进行描述，
here's how to organize your database system,
这是如何组织你的数据库系统，
and then you can see different implementations of it.
然后你可以看到它的不同实现。
Through SQL you can then see how,
通过 SQL ，你可以看到如何，
you know they are certain slots, sort of things in slot slotted pages.
它们是某种插槽页面的东西。
All right.
好的。
All right, so in the sake of time.
好的，为了时间着想。
I think I'm going to skip.
我想我要跳过。
This will segue into next class,
这将进入下一节课，
but the tuple itself is just going to be a sequence of bytes.
但是， tuple 本身只是一个字节序列，
There's some header and then a byte sequence,
有一些头，然后是字节序列，
and then it's up for the database system to know
然后是数据库系统知道，
how to interpret those bytes based on the type and based on the values that you're looking at.
如何根据类型和你正在查看的值来解释这些字节。
So again, we'll cover this next class,
我们将在下一节课上讲，
but the way to think about this is,
但是思考这个问题的方法是，
there'll be some header,
这里有一些头，
that contains information on whether this tuple [] or not,
其中包含关于 tuple 是否[]的信息，
we can store, you know, whether or not we want to store,
我们可以存储，
keep track of what columns have nulls
跟踪哪些列具有空值，
and then then the execution engine will know how to jump to different offsets within the tuple based on the schema.
然后执行引擎将知道如何根据模式跳到 tuple 中的不同偏移量。
So again, we'll cover this in next class,
我们将在下一节课中讨论这个，
but just to finish up.
但只是作为结束。
Again, what we what do we discussed today,
我们今天讨论了什么，
there's a database system to maintain a database,
有一个数据库系统来维护一个数据库，
that data is going be tracked in across different files and broke up into pages
数据将被不同的文件跟踪，并分解成页面，
and then we have different ways to keep track of those pages,
然后我们有不同的方法来跟踪这些页面，
keep track of what's and how to store things in those pages
跟踪哪些以及如何在这些页面中存储内容，
and then next class,
然后下一节课，
we'll talk about what how to store actually the tuples.
我们将讨论如何存储 tuple 。
So, again, a lot of discuss next next class,
所以，下一节课会有很多讨论，
have a good weekend, see you.
周末愉快，再见。